Are you ready for some Kerbal Space Program?
I was about to say Kerbal Space Program.
Couldn't even say that right.
Guys, I just ran my hands under the sink in hot water.
Nothing like heating your extremities, okay?
We've reached that part of the year where all my extremities go cold every single day.
I need a very specific temperature, pressure, humidity and all that to be comfortable.
I'm like a lizard.
I think I need a heat lamp or something on my feet and my hands.
Ah, man, we are back with some streaming.
It's been a while.
I had a small secret stream.
Well, secret, secret, but...
We did a little bit of GeoGuessr and, well...
I was hoping to play some World of Warcraft that day, but...
Couldn't do it.
The servers were full and not working.
So, yeah.
Haven't even tried it since.
But maybe at some point.
How y'all doing?
How are you all doing today?
Another wonderful week has begun.
I just watched Blueprints.
I can't speak today, man.
I'm just mumbling my words.
It's been a while.
Why did you put intro music in it?
Because you just played it.
That's why, Kado Kako.
That is why I did it.
I knew you were doing it, because I saw you through the window.
I'm out there.
Sometimes.
Just had a terribly toxic teammate in Night Rain.
That sucks, man.
Just move on from it.
Assholes be assholes.
Don't let them stay in your mind.
Rent free, you know?
Easier said than done, of course.
Are you gonna use any mods?
Yes, I am!
I have installed some graphical mods.
Some mods that enhance the graphics and the visuals and the sounds.
I have installed nothing that affects gameplay, of course.
But I've installed all the graphics stuff.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, so let me just say this right off the bangle here.
I did already play a little bit of this game.
Many, many, many, many years ago.
It's changed a lot since then.
There's like a campaign now with actual progression.
And...
I don't actually remember much.
I did land on the moon back then, but I think I had access to everything that was there.
The game looked like ass at the time.
It was super buggy.
It was just falling apart at the seams, you know?
It was held together by spit and duct tape and some hope.
So, uh...
I confirmed already in-game.
It looks a lot better, especially with the mods now.
It's crazy what modding has done for this game.
Holy shit.
It looks really nice.
I mean, considering what it looks like unmodded, you know?
The game is still a little rough around the edges, I guess.
But we're gonna have some fun with this.
We're gonna play the campaign, of course.
So apparently there's like a tech tree now.
You can unlock things gradually so you don't get overwhelmed.
Which is awesome.
This game gives me so much nostalgia.
Love it.
I feel like a lot of games I play give you guys nostalgia.
It still looks bad without mods.
Yeah, I know.
I saw it.
At least I have a much better computer now than I did last time I tried this.
I don't even think there was a campaign mode back when I played this.
Like...
I landed on the moon and something else as well.
I think some other moon.
Or planet.
I think it was...
I think two moons.
On the first planet.
I landed on those.
But...
Bro.
Minmus?
Maybe.
Could've...
I think so.
Could be.
But it's been so long, man.
We're gonna play it for real now.
You know what I thought back then?
And I haven't changed my opinion at all on gaming since then.
Is that I saw it and was like, damn, this is actually kind of fun.
I'm gonna wait until it's actually finished.
And here we are.
The game is finished.
Yeah, I did install the amazing clouds.
I wouldn't say they look better than Microsoft Flight Simulator.
That's kind of crazy talk.
They look good.
But not better than MSFS.
Come on.
I know nothing about this game.
Well, that's great, man.
We can figure out together.
Well, mostly me.
I'm three years old.
In some far planet out there.
Yeah.
You probably are.
That would be a very slowly...
orbiting planet.
It looks very Halo CE?
Wait, what?
I haven't played Halo, so I wouldn't know.
What's the plan for today?
We're landing on Jupiter?
I don't think Jupiter is in the game.
It's like a made-up solar system.
So it wouldn't even be called a solar system, because it's not the sun, so it would be called a star system.
It's a made-up star system.
With, like, different planets and...
Okay, so for those that don't know what this game is, let me try and explain it.
It's kind of like a sandbox game.
But now they have added some progression and campaign mechanics to it.
So...
The gameplay goal is to simply explore, pretty much.
It's to see if you can land on some of the planets.
You know, go explore the surfaces of different orbital or bodies up there.
You know?
It's kind of cool.
It's a great idea.
It's about exploring.
And it's a lot about trial and error too.
Making shit blow up and stuff.
You know?
I think it's gonna be a lot of fun.
I'm actually so excited for this.
So Minecraft but in space?
Not really.
Not at all.
But, yeah.
You'll see when we get started.
Oh, and I just wanna say this.
While I do have a physics background, I have been formally trained in physics.
And, you know, astrophysics specifically.
That does not have anything to do with space travel, okay?
Like, I know some stuff.
But I'm not...
You can't...
You're not gonna expect me to be like an expert on this.
Cuz I'm not, okay?
We're gonna be blowing up some rockets.
We're gonna be killing some kerbals.
And it's gonna be fun.
I do know some stuff, of course.
That's gonna give me a little bit of a boost, of course.
But other than that...
It's funny.
Because I also have a real life friend.
His name is Peter.
And...
Every time...
He asks me about something from physics, right?
Maybe some kind of news about some quantum...
I don't know...
Discovery or whatever, you know?
And then he asks me and I go, I don't know.
And he's like, but you're an astrophysicist!
Like, that doesn't mean I know everything!
Okay?
It means I know a lot about a very specific kind of narrow thing.
Other than that, I'm pretty much clueless.
Like, I don't know how to fucking boil an egg, you know?
That's... that's it.
So we're gonna be learning.
Oh, you're an astrophysicist?
I just name every star.
Oh!
Not to mention it's been a while since I actually got formal training.
And all that stuff.
What is the narrow stuff you know a lot about?
Well, you know, like, planets and stars, galaxies, black holes.
Not actual space travel.
Like, I know what a Homan transfer is.
I also know what a translunar injection is.
Like, I understand high-level ideas, but I'm not, like, an expert on any of that.
You know what I mean?
Would you say astrophysics is nice for creative people?
I don't know.
I think it's nice for people that are intrigued by the universe, you know?
This is how you learn.
Exactly.
A woman transfer?
No, no.
A Homan transfer.
I probably didn't even pronounce that right.
It's basically a way to, you know, go from one orbit to another.
We'll figure it out.
Um, so I was actually looking...
Hold on.
I'm gonna...
Switch over here.
There we go!
Are you ready?
Uh, let me switch.
Whoops, that's not switching.
Click on this.
There we are.
By the way, I put the chat there.
Because I noticed some UI elements in the top left, top right, bottom right, bottom left, so I don't know.
Hopefully it's gonna be fine.
I'll try and adjust it live.
So we don't have issues.
Uh, what is that?
Like a little thing.
That's probably fine.
Yeah, the chat's gonna be there for now.
We'll see how it goes.
Uh, so apparently there's difficulties and stuff, so...
I will actually ask you guys...
Like, I'm drawn to heart.
I am.
Is that a terrible idea?
Let me ask.
Rotund, I'm actually asking.
Here.
Like, what do you suggest for someone like me?
Terrible.
Yes, do it.
Moderate.
Normal.
Dude, I'm not gonna go normal, come on.
Let the game make you cry.
No Terraria situation again.
That's a misnomer.
People...
I didn't quit Terraria because it was difficult.
I quit it because I didn't like the game.
That's a different thing.
I don't mind hard games.
The thing I'm kinda intrigued about is this.
You see, it says, allow reverting flights.
Here, you can't do it.
But here you can.
You know what I mean?
Feels kinda crazy that you can do that.
Moderate, please.
You will cry without reverting.
Okay, we should do a poll.
I'm gonna do a poll.
Um...
Hard...
Or...
Moderate.
Cause I'm not going normal, come on.
It's gonna be three...
Uh, two minutes.
There you go.
Whoa!
Okay, the vast majority are saying moderate.
So, maybe it is...
Oh, is it because the game is, like, not super stable and I can get fucked by...
Like, bugs and stuff?
Okay, well...
Guys, I think we're gonna go moderate then.
And you know what?
Listen.
Worst case, if it's too easy, we can always ramp it up, right?
I guess.
Like, it's not really that big a deal.
We can always go higher, down the road, if it turns out to be too easy.
I'm gonna be eating my words.
I'm gonna...
I'm gonna be eating those words for sure.
Put hardcore?
There's no hardcore.
There's custom.
That just, you know, allows me to do whatever.
Okay, we're gonna go moderate.
It's the vast majority of people recommending that.
I'm not gonna go normal.
I want moderate.
Okay.
Moderate.
So we're gonna go career.
In career mode, you have to manage all aspects of your space program.
Funds, reputation, and science are all active, and contracts are available at Mission Control.
Save name?
Uh...
God, I don't know.
It's just...
Kerbal Space Program?
It's just the save name, right?
It's not actually...
Or...
Maybe it's actually the name of the...
Space Program.
Hmm...
I know I'm very inventive.
Flag.
Hey!
I like that one!
That kinda looks like...
Ooh, that's also kinda nice.
Wait, what's that?
Sean's what?
Who the hell is Sean?
I actually kinda like these designs.
Ooh, that's a good one.
Retro.
I like that one.
Let's go with that one.
KSP.
This is just a space program.
I think we're ready.
Here we go!
Let me see if the chat is correct.
Ah, maybe we can move it down just a bit.
Make it a bit smaller.
Oh god.
Something like that.
Oh, wait, no.
There we go.
Maybe we put it over here, actually.
That's probably better.
I like that.
Let's put it there.
Okay.
Welcome to the Space Center.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Gene Kerman.
That has to be a reference to Gene Krantz, right?
Who was a...
I don't know if he's called a flight director, but he was one of the guys during...
Fuck, what's it called?
The initial missions, you know, leading up to the moon landing.
Flight director and your guide for this quick introduction.
This is the Space Center.
From here you can manage all aspects of the space program.
Feel free to have a look around.
Hold the right mouse button to move the camera.
Right click over the Space Center facilities to view more about them.
And left click when you're ready to head inside.
If you need more information, check out the training section on the main menu.
Maybe I should have done that.
Thanks, I've got it.
Uh, the game is kinda loud.
Let's turn it down just a bit.
35.
That's a very aggressive and loud, like, background ambiance.
Okay.
Here we are, man.
Look at these visuals.
Like, the game, when I just installed it, looked absolutely terrible.
Then I installed these mods, and now it's frickin' amazing.
So, there we are.
Uh, let me just get acquainted here.
I'm guessing this is my money.
Uh, not sure what that is.
Maybe it's the progression thing.
These are my mods.
Uh, administration building.
Astronaut complex.
Launch pad.
I'm actually kinda glad that I put it on moderate now, guys.
Just looking at all this right now makes me think it's probably the right choice.
Uh, space plane hangar.
Tracking station.
Wait, at the tracking station, all ongoing missions can be viewed and focused.
Landed craft can be recovered from here as well.
Yiggle assembly building.
Um...
Okay.
Look at this.
Basic rocketry.
How hard can rocket science be anyway?
That is honestly my thought process right now.
Okay.
Oh, research.
So that's, I guess, the progression.
Um...
Currency.
Okay, I don't wanna read too much about these right now.
I don't have any of this anyway, so...
But it says I can...
Wait.
Okay, yeah.
Not enough science to research this node.
Got it.
Require start.
Oh, that's that one.
Got it.
Oh, so this is what I have now.
EVA jetpack.
Personal parachute?
Okay.
Archives.
Oh, here we go.
Look at this.
The sun.
Moho.
I actually kinda wanna learn about the, uh...
The star system here.
We are on Kerbin.
Yeah, okay.
So these are the ones I've landed on in the past.
Why can't I...
There's nothing...
I thought that would be like something I could read, but okay.
Maybe I'm missing something.
What's this?
Oh, search.
Holy shit.
Whoa!
Look at all this?
What is that?
Air brakes.
Wait, there's helicopters?
Wait, what?
That was definitely not, uh, a thing when this game first came out.
At least I don't remember.
Jesus Christ.
Okay, actually, I don't wanna get spoiled.
I don't wanna see what's at the end.
I shouldn't look at this.
Um...
Research and development.
Okay.
I actually wanna read this.
So, at the R&D facility, our team of scientists works hard to crunch the data received from mission experiments.
Here, all research technologies can be viewed and new ones discovered.
Right.
Mission control.
At the mission control facility, all available contracts can be managed.
It also offers a very nice view of the launch sites for any who are brave enough to be so close to a launching craft.
Hmm.
This is the launch pad.
Can I actually...
Get over there, somehow?
Ah!
Here we go.
Whoa, whoa, the camera is so sensitive.
Hey, look, my flag!
Oh, it's- I can't zoom anymore.
Uh, okay.
Upgrade.
The launch pad is where vessels built at the VAB are launched.
We are reasonably conf- reasonably confident it's at a safe enough distance from everything else.
Okay.
What is that down there?
Looks like some kind of bunker.
Whoa.
Okay.
Oh, God.
Can I- Okay, there we go.
Maybe it's easy to just click over here, actually.
Seems a little, uh, gimmicky the way the camera moves.
Astronaut complex.
Let me actually click on this.
Okay, so we can hire Kerbals, and we have four active Kerbals right now.
And I'm assuming we can lose these, and it's gonna be terrible.
Pilot, Engineer, Scientist, and Pilot.
What does that mean?
Pilots provide assistance in flying the vessel.
Effects stability assist.
Full vessel control without COMnet access?
Dude, I don't know what any of this shit means.
Engineers are capable of repairing broken parts, if at all possible.
Effects increase resource converter efficiency.
Increase drill efficiency?
Deployed power generation units.
Wait, this game seems a lot deeper than I remember.
Like, you could launch rockets, and that was pretty much it.
Back when this game came out.
Scientists can boost the value of data from science experiments.
Run experiments from EVA, that's cool.
Extra vehicular activity.
Okay, and another pilot.
Jebediah.
Okay, I like the music.
Space plane hangar.
Welcome to the space plane hangar.
Hello, I'm Wernher von Kerman.
Chief Rocketry Engineer.
Nice, that's another reference to the German rocket dude.
This is the space plane hangar.
Here is where we build spacecraft that later will take off from the runway.
On your left, you'll find components to construct your own space plane.
Select the starting part, then attach others to it to build.
You can then have a look around with the right mouse button.
Or the arrow keys.
We just got this place cleaned up.
So try not to mess it up too much.
If you need more guidance on how to build spacecraft, have a look at the training section.
At the main menu.
That's the second time they are referencing me to that.
I don't know if I should.
Um...
I guess I just start launching shit, right?
On... onion?
So this is everything I have right now.
I almost have nothing.
Mystery Goo Containment Unit.
Okay.
Jetpack and parachute.
Let me just leave this.
We're touring the Space Center right now.
Astronaut Complex.
The Astronaut Complex contains the living and recreation spaces for all our crew members.
New applicants also apply here to be recruited.
Oh, I've been in here already.
Fuck.
Uh, what about this one?
Mission Control.
Here we go.
Welcome to Mission Control.
Please make a selection.
Gather scientific data from Curbin.
Okay, so we got missions.
Offer expires in four days.
Escape the atmosphere.
Orbit Curb...
Dude, I'm so excited about this.
What is this?
The Curbin World First Record Keeping Society.
Alright.
Um...
What are the founding principles of Curbin World First Record Keeping Society?
Is to continue to advance the frontiers of science.
We still have unchecked items on our list of records to break and would like to change that.
But really, there's no sense in us still talking while there's science to be done.
Shall we get to it?
This reminds me a little of, uh, Portal.
You know that, um...
Character that is all about science?
Science must be done.
Give us a quick, uh, crew report before launching.
It's fine if any of the lights on the control panel are flashing.
Just give it a swift kick.
Okay, prestige is trivial.
Recover or transmit any science experiment data from Curbin to achieve this goal.
Okay, but what is this?
Achieve goal incomplete.
Wait, what is the difference?
I...
It...
These are rewards, but what is this then?
Another reward?
Okay.
So we get one science from it.
And we get two stars.
Oh, well, maybe it's difficulty.
This one has one star.
I think so.
Look, Orbit Curbin has three stars.
Um...
Accept contract.
Launcher first vessel.
Uh, let's see here.
One of the founding principles of Curbin World First Record Keeping Society is to continue to advance the frontiers of science.
Nobody has set any space records yet.
It would probably be best to just start by getting something off the launch pad.
Then we can start worrying about things like survivability.
But really, there's no sense in us still talking while there's science to be done.
Shall we get to it?
We'd like to officially start off the space program with a bang.
A very controlled bang, preferably.
Launch your first vessel off of the launch pad or the runway to achieve this goal.
Um, oh, active.
Wait, wait, should I actually take more than one though?
I don't know if this is a good idea.
Ah, I guess there's no reason not to.
I guess they do expire though, right?
Oh wait, expires never.
Oh, never mind.
I thought it said it expi- It says offer expires.
Huh.
Well then I don't understand.
Oh, active contracts too.
Max is too.
So I can't actually take more.
Ah.
I see.
Okay, well, in that case.
Cool.
And I can see my contracts at any time, I guess.
No alarms.
Time warp.
I know there's a key bind to do this.
But I don't know which one.
Um...
What's that?
Manual.
Ooh!
Wow, okay, so it doesn't pop up with anything.
I actually like that.
That you have to sort of go in here if you're confused.
That's cool.
This reminds me of Total War.
Because in Total War, they have this sort of encyclopedia in the game.
You know, and whenever you're confused about something, you just open that and search.
It's almost like a Wikipedia, but inside the game, you know?
Kinda nice.
Doesn't look like I can search, though.
But okay.
Delta V?
Tools?
Sweet.
Holy shit.
Let's actually just consult this when we need it.
I like that.
Administration building.
What is this?
Mortimer Kerman is in finances.
Linus Kerman is in science.
Public relations.
Why do you wear this?
Gus Kerman.
Cannot afford setup cost.
Not enough reputation.
Okay, so this is reputation.
We can likely raise some money by exploiting the attention that we get out of new successful ventures.
To remind the well-to-do Kerbals out there that we could use their support.
And the contents of their wallets.
This is probably gonna be seen as a bit cheeky of us, so be prepared to face some backlash from the public.
Okay, it looks like I can only do these two though.
Research rights sellout.
We could make a quick buck from the science the R&D team has collected by selling exclusive research rights to the highest bidder.
Yes, that means we wouldn't be able to make use of that science ourselves.
But for exclusive rights, I'm sure we could fetch a pretty penny from some large agency or conglomerate.
Ah, okay, so this is like...
Like the marketplace from Age of Empires.
Or whatever it's called, you know?
Where you can trade...
Certain resources for other resources.
What's this?
Funds to... Okay.
This seems kinda confusing, I'm not gonna do that now.
Tracking station.
Welcome to the tracking station!
Hi again!
This is the tracking station facility, also called the TSF.
And here you can view all of the solar system, as well as the current positions and trajectories of all ongoing missions.
When you have missions in progress, you'll see them listed on the panel at your left.
And you'll be able to take command of them from this screen.
I like this music.
It's so fitting.
Sometimes contracts may require specific destinations in orbit, or on the surface.
Those will also be visible here.
Lastly, if you wanted to see this same map viewed during flight, just hit the M key.
Okay.
You got it.
Oh my god, look at all this.
Yo, I really like this song!
Dude...
Desert Launch Site!
There's something else there, what is that?
Desert Airfield.
Kerbal Space Center.
Island Airfield.
Boomerang Launch Site.
Very cool.
Toggle debris, probes...
Rovers?!
Yo, wait a minute, wait, wait!
We get to make rovers?!
I wanna make a rover!
Lander, I suspected.
Stations!
Oh, I guess that...
Okay, this is default not showing.
Toggle bases, planes, relays!
What the hell, bro?
Oh!
Oh, the sites.
Deployed Science.
ComNet Network.
What is that?
The moon!
Look!
Beautiful.
Should there be another...
Oh wait, I can zoom, right?
Oh, here we go.
Minmus, look at that one.
Oh man.
Eve.
Okay, so the closest planet is this one.
Moho.
Oh, I can't...
Oh, I can zoom, okay.
Sweet.
I guess this is the...
The hot one.
I wonder if temperature is gonna matter.
You know, like...
We're close to the sun here, on the sunny side.
Are we gonna have to...
Worry about overheating or shit like that?
I don't know.
That would be kinda cool.
Oh, they actually just call it the sun!
Interesting.
So I guess solar system makes sense here.
Okay, that's, uh, Kerbin.
Duna.
Looks like the Mars equivalent.
Duel.
Elo.
Oh, that one has a bit of an inclination on it, look!
I wonder how it ended up like that.
Hmm.
Maybe it didn't form from the same cloud.
Drace.
God, I love this music.
I don't wanna leave this screen.
This music is so good.
Year one, day one, zero hours, eight minutes.
It's only been eight minutes?
There's no way.
Contracts.
Gather scientific data from Kerbin.
Launch your first vessel.
Recover or transmit any science experiment data from Kerbin to achieve this goal.
Okay, okay.
Got it.
Alarm clock.
What's this?
Oh!
Wait, what?
Cut off?
Oh wait, maybe I need to...
Zoom?
Whoa!
Okay, here we go.
Yeah, that's definitely the Mars equivalent.
What is this?
Wait, what?
I don't know what's happening.
Okay, I don't know what that means.
Here we go, physical characteristics.
320 kilometers.
That's it?
Like nothing.
It's a small planet.
Ha!
Three day rotation.
Sphere of influence.
48,000 kilometers.
Atmosphere, yes.
Uh, ASL?
Uh, what does that mean?
Is that like, um...
Above surface level?
Something like that?
I don't know.
Or maybe, uh...
I don't know, actually.
It's gotta be.
At surface level, maybe?
0.3G?
I'm assuming Kerbin is 1G?
Okay.
Also known as the red dot, that you can see if you squint at it really hard.
Duna has long been a wonder to Kerbal kind.
The planet has been held in much awe, due to its striking red color and stark contrast to the color green.
Haha!
That last sentence is kinda random, but okay.
I mean, sure.
Uh, okay.
Cool.
We're gonna investigate that more later.
Whoa.
Yeah, you can tell the game is like, not super optimized.
Whoa, what's this?
Research and development.
Oh, did I click on it?
I didn't mean to click on it.
Whoops.
I thought a pop-up just happened.
Um...
I actually kinda wanna figure out how to, uh, so you can apparently advance time with a keybind.
I need to find the, uh, hotkeys.
Wait, what?
Hold on.
There's no hotkeys?
Wait a minute.
Time out!
Back.
Input.
What?!
Why is that not part of the game?!
Like, why do I have to go to the menu for this?
Hello?
That's messed up, bro.
I don't like that.
Um...
Let me see here.
Yeah, space...
Space is to launch.
I know that.
Vessel.
Oh my god, look at all this shit.
Dude, so what?
I have to go to the menu every time I wanna look at a keybind?
There's no way.
That's terrible.
Full throttle.
Water bottle.
Brakes.
Okay, landing here on G.
That's the same keybind I have in, uh, Microsoft Flight Simulator.
Heh heh.
I forgot what I was looking for.
Steering with AD, WS.
Fuck.
Oh my god, look at all these.
I may have to write this down, I'm not even kidding.
If I had a printer, I would print this right now.
Increase time warp!
Dot.
Oh, oh, okay, okay, yeah, yeah.
Focus next vessel.
Okay.
Got it.
Let's go back.
Sorry about that.
Okay, let's try and launch a rocket, shall we?
Uh...
Oh, uh, right, okay.
Here we go.
So, we have, we have some, uh, missions here.
Gather scientific data from Kerbin, and launch first vessel.
So, obviously, we're gonna need, um...
A fuel tank.
Or, like, an engine.
How many do I actually have?
Is this showing everything?
Maybe there's, like...
Maybe there's, okay, maybe there's showing everything.
This is, like, advanced, uh, filters.
Build crew cargo switch editor?
I guess we need this.
While considered by some to be little more than a trash bin full of boom, the RT5 can be seen in use at many space programs.
Perhaps possibly because it is the only option for many space programs.
But, nevertheless, this small booster provides a nice kick to lift small payloads to considerable heights.
Use with caution, though.
Once lit, solid fuel motors cannot be put out until the fuel runs out.
Right.
It's like real life.
Okay.
Uh, then we need to control it.
Parts.
KV-1 onion re-entry module.
The design bureau cried when the finance department cried.
That's your lot.
I don't know what that means.
Oh, wait a minute.
I need to be, uh, thinking about money here.
How much money do I have?
18,000.
And this one costs how much?
200.
Oh, that's nothing.
That's a cheap, uh, solid fuel booster.
This one costs 600.
These both cost 600.
Wait, what's the difference?
Except design.
Mass plus passenger mass.
Tolerance.
Oh, this one can tolerate more impact.
Haha!
They write G's as G-E-E-S.
That's funny.
4000 kPa.
Oh, look at this one.
Max temperature internal?
And skin?
I guess it's related to, uh, how fast you can, uh, re-enter the atmosphere.
Or, I guess, in any case, how fast you can go through the atmosphere.
How do I actually...
Oh.
Monopropellants.
Dude, this game has changed like crazy.
Used to be, like, you just put a couple boosters on it, and you go, you know?
There's like all kinds of information now.
This part cannot be placed in a storage container, but can be manipulated in EVA construction.
Okay.
Not sure what that means.
Data transmitter antenna type internal.
Okay.
Oh, wait.
What's happening?
Technical issues.
Move... Oh, the chat!
Oh, fuck!
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry about that.
Sorry about that.
Let's put it, like, here.
Let's put it there.
That's probably better.
Or maybe up here, yeah.
There we go.
Thank you for letting me know.
I hope it wasn't terrible for a long time there.
My bad.
Okay.
So, we definitely want one of these.
I'm just gonna take this.
Okay.
Looks like a diving bell, doesn't it?
Looks like one of those...
I forgot the name of it.
Modular girder segment.
Build the structure of your dreams with the Maxo Construction Toys Modular Girder segment.
Cool.
I wish it would sort of, um...
It's very...
I don't know how to explain it.
Robotics?
Wait, what?!
What do you mean robotics?
Coupling...
Oh!
Yeah!
So, you can also decouple things in this game.
So, like, say you want to make a...
A staged rocket, right?
You can do that.
I think that's kind of cool.
Payload aerodynamics.
Basic fin.
Maybe we should do that.
Speaking of, uh...
Aerodynamic.
This doesn't look very aerodynamic, does it?
I feel like this is more suited for the ocean and not the outer space.
Am I crazy?
Give me, uh, this one.
Um...
Yeah, much better.
Except, why isn't it, uh...
Fully, you know, spiky?
This simple bolt-on aluminum fin may...
May not be the cutting edge of aerospace engineering.
But it's dirt cheap and will make your rocket slightly less unstable.
Okay.
I guess I'll...
I mean...
Look how cute this thing is, bro.
Holy shit.
That looks so dumb.
I don't know what it looks like.
It looks like, um...
I don't know.
I feel like I've recognized this shape from somewhere.
Communication...
Science!
Mystery...
What is this?
This unit was something one of our engineers came upon while dumpster diving.
Um...
While researching alternative applications for existing technologies.
It's a sealed container which appears to be filled with a strange-looking substance.
We couldn't reach in or break the canister open.
But watching how the goo behaves when subjected to different situations...
Could be very educational.
Okay.
I guess if you go to Zero-G...
The goo would be, you know, floating.
That's nice.
This is a cargo part that can be placed inside inventories.
Okay.
By the way, this music...
I recognize this from...
Well, obviously, Kerbal Space Program.
But it's also a song that has been used a lot in, like, YouTube videos, you know?
Observe mystery goo.
Collectible data.
Rerunnable.
X.
It's resettable.
Cleanup requires electric charge?
Brother.
Ah...
I'm a little overwhelmed.
Wait!
Speaking of...
Shouldn't we have, like, people in here?
Oh my god.
Wheel authority...
Oh, I guess reaction wheels?
Yeah.
Oh, I guess how powerful they are?
Reaction wheels normal.
SAS only.
Pilot only.
Oh my god.
Toggle torque.
Oh, okay, so you can just disable them.
Antenna rating 5...
I don't know.
Okay.
Configure ve...
Oh!
Hell yeah!
We're gonna call this...
Uh...
Uno.
It is a...
I guess it's just...
I guess it's a ship.
Wait, name priority?
The setting with the highest priority within the vessel will be used to name the vessel and set the vessel type.
Okay.
This craft will be named Uno when launched.
Nice.
Control point default reversed.
Lights on, lights off.
Toggle flag.
Wait, what?
Is there a flag?
I'm not seeing a flag.
Am I blind?
Oh!
Oh shit!
How do I zoom?
Ah.
Haha!
Look at that one.
That's nice.
I actually kinda...
I really love this design actually.
That's nice.
Oh no, no, no.
That's the way.
Electric charge.
I guess you can...
Wait, variant.
Oh.
Cool.
Oh, I like that one.
Yeah, I like that one.
Dude, there's so many options here.
Wait, what?
What does this do?
Oh, is it like I can type?
Ah, okay.
Okay, so this is like dragging and now I can type.
Sweet.
And we can pin it, I guess, so we can't...
So it stays.
Okay.
Whoops.
I need to...
Let's see here.
Thrust limiter.
Shroud.
Wait, he's in the game?
I'm kidding.
I don't know actually what this means in this case, but...
Solid fuel.
I can adjust this.
Yo, let's make it match the winglets here.
I like that.
Uh, okay.
Okay, so let me think.
Uh, so we launch...
And we want to get back down, right?
So we need this.
No, actually, that's a personal parachute.
We need this one.
The MK-16 parachute might be considered by some to be little more than a random stitching together of the surplus parts it is in fact made from.
But the fact remains that the MK-16 has been widely accepted as a generally better alternative to being in freefall.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
I guess it goes on top.
Oh, that's beautiful.
Look at that.
Can I change the color?
Wait, altitude?
Oh, wait.
I can...
I can adjust when this will unfold?
I don't know.
Leave it at default.
Minimum pressure?
Whoa.
Wait a minute.
So wait, what is the difference actually between these other than this shape?
Ablader.
Resource ablader.
Oh, that's the stuff used to protect against heat, isn't it?
Ablative covering.
Minimum crew to operate one.
Crew must include a pilot.
Okay.
Wait, why does it say untitled spacecraft?
I thought I already did this.
Uno.
It's the first.
Whoops.
Can you please close the thing?
Okay, there we go.
Alright.
I think we're ready.
Also, what's this?
Center of mass overlay.
Cool.
Center of thrust.
Aerodynamic overlay.
Not actually sure what that means.
Like, what is that telling me?
Um...
Okay, so this I remember.
So you have, like, staging over here, where you, uh, do this in sequence.
Okay.
What's that?
Thruster weight ratio, seven.
Oh, we're definitely getting off the ground.
Burns for nine seconds?
I don't want to reset.
Export craft.
Are we ready?
I think we're ready.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Oh, what's this?
Crew.
Ah!
There we go.
I was wondering where that setting was here.
I was looking for that.
So he's a pilot.
Uh, we gotta put him in there, right?
Cargo.
Oh wait, so, wait, he already has?
A parachute?
Why is this not full?
Switch...
No, I don't want to switch editor.
Select an...
Oh, okay.
So if I...
Ah, okay.
So wait.
Actually, there's gotta be a way to like...
Align this.
See, this is where I would love to open the menu and actually just look at hotkeys for this.
But, uh, nope.
You gotta go into the main menu for that for some fucking reason.
Doesn't make any sense.
I don't know what reroute means.
Select a set of two or more parts to reroute.
I don't know what I did.
I'm stalling!
I am.
Uh, we should just go, man.
Let's go.
Holy crap.
This is gonna go bad.
It looks so dumb!
Look at that!
And look at this guy!
EVA?
Oh, that's cool.
Can I actually flip these?
Beautiful.
Oh!
Look at my fluffy little hands!
Okay, I wanna go back.
Take me back.
Toggle time mode?
Oh, universal time?
Mission estimated time, I guess?
Yeah, T+.
Wait, how do I actually...
Go back?
Oop!
I did something.
There we go.
WHOA!
Bro, I need to print the fucking keybinds.
I have no idea how I just did that.
Okay, are you ready?
We gotta press space and then we go.
And then we gotta press space again for the parachute.
Oh!
Sweet!
Yeah, that only lasted like nine seconds or something.
This is great, man.
Yeah.
I feel like...
Okay, I know I can't judge it yet based on the physics stuff, but it feels exactly like this sort of physics from the very first time the game came out, you know?
WHOA!
I accidentally put it into something I shouldn't have...
Oh my god, what have I done?
Nope, nope.
I think it's inverted.
Oh, actually I just did not touch it, then it stabilizes automatically.
Because we're moving upwards right now and we actually are aerodynamic.
Where's the parachute?
I pressed space!
Uh oh.
I probably fucked it up.
Oh no.
Oh, RCS!
Don't I need thrusters for that?
Oh!
Well there it is!
But wait, we're not at a thousand.
I thought this would release at a thousand.
Okay, I guess we just wait.
I think we're- I think we're fine here.
It's a good start, man.
Oh wait, I forgot about my missions.
Um...
Launch first vessel achieved!
Hell yeah!
Shoot destroyed by air forces and heat!
Ah, fuck!
Which work?
We're fucked.
I mean, we are- you know what we are right now?
We're a missile.
Going straight down.
This is actually the worst time to be aerodynamic.
No!
God damn it.
You know what it is actually?
I shouldn't have, um...
I shouldn't have, uh...
Gone straight up.
I should have taken a parabolic arc, you know?
Uh...
Because that's just recipe for disaster.
How do I...
Flight results!
Catastrophic failure!
Hot damn!
20,000 meters achieved!
That was fast that we actually did that.
655 meters per second.
Wow.
Shoot destroyed by air forces and heat!
Okay.
Uno crashed into Kerbin.
Jebediah Kerbin was killed.
RT5 flea solid fuel booster collided into surface.
The basic fin collided.
And the parachute collided.
Well...
Oh!
But look at this!
We can just revert to launch!
This is what I mean!
Like, okay.
Obviously it's good for, you know, beginners.
But it also kind of feels weird to just do that, right?
But I guess we're learning.
What is that over there?
I think it's like a little, uh...
Protective bunker where they can watch the launch.
Uh...
Okay.
So we're gonna...
We're gonna take a parabolic arc now.
Wait, am I ready?
Oh, wait, wait, wait!
Uh...
Gather scientific data from Kerbin.
And how do I do that?
Wait a minute.
I need to, uh...
Let me look at this.
Science.
Science from data.
Turning data into science.
When you perform activities, a report with the data is generated.
The primary method to extract the science from that data and advance Kerbin knowledge is to get the data back to Kerbin.
You can see all the options for the report in the result window.
Okay.
The recovery and transmit bar show the amount of total science possible.
And the amount this report will earn.
Bring it back to Kerbin.
Yeah, you don't want to die.
That's bad.
Or have the vessel explode.
By choosing keep experiment, the report will be stored to be recovered with the Kerbal or vessel on Kerbin surface.
This usually nets you the best science return and is the only way to extract all the possible science from any experiment and subject combination.
Okay.
Experimenting for profit.
The most obvious way to generate science is through activities.
Dude, I gotta take a piss real bad.
I gotta read this first though.
At its simplest, this involves observations by the crew or...
Crew or EVA reports.
And works its way through performing experiments all the way to processing data in a lab?
Wait, is that actually...
Maybe it's just flavor text.
Maybe they don't actually mean that.
A simple action the crew perform as required.
Once you have done these, you will rarely get any reward for repeating them with the same subject.
Okay.
Experiment reports.
These involve the use of science parts to perform experiments.
I don't think I ha...
Oh wait, we have the...
We have the...
The goo, don't we?
For example, you won't get any seismology readings written wrong.
If your vessel is in space.
I mean, that makes sense, I guess.
Um...
I need to...
How... wait, how do I actually...
Space center.
I gotta see something real quick.
Mission control.
Active.
Give us a quick crew report before launching.
It's fine if any of the lights on the control panel are flashing.
Just give it a swift kick.
Okay.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Standing by to launch.
Oh, okay, okay.
I thought I reverted.
And I actually...
Okay, so I'm actually on the pad.
Makes sense.
Uh...
Okay, so we gotta go in here.
Obviously, we're not gonna give anything a swift kick.
That was kind of flavor text, but...
Can I...
Oh, I can also zoom, look.
Food?
Not food!
Okay.
Laundry.
Toothbrushes.
Alright.
I mean, I guess that's...
Needed.
The essentials.
Um...
Go EVA!
I love these guys.
This is fantastic.
Okay.
Should I...
Let go?
Oh my god.
Well...
Shit.
Here we are.
Oh wait, I can...
I can probably transfer things then.
EVA report.
EVA report from Launchpad.
I don't think a spacesuit was entirely necessary to get here, was it?
100% science value.
8 myths.
I just wanted to see what would happen.
Okay, nothing happened.
I guess you have to be in the air for that.
Uh...
Overwrite existing EVA report.
No.
Review report.
Keep experiment.
Oh, that's cool.
Look at that.
Okay.
Now, how do I get back up though?
Oh, I think I can jump.
Wait, did it say climb?
I think it said climb.
Come here.
Can I...
Target Uno.
I don't know.
Dude, I swear this game was easier to play.
Back when it came out.
Let's talk a little gear.
Wait.
If I go here...
Okay.
Then I go back?
Oh, I thought maybe I would be inside again.
Dude, I love this little view here.
Maybe I should put the helmet back on.
Wait.
What's that say?
Oh my god, dude.
What do I do here?
Oh!
Recover vessel.
Mission summary!
For Jeff and Diakirvan!
EVA report from Launchpad.
We got 2.2 science.
Data gathered.
We got the jetpack and parachute.
No XP gain.
I mean, no surprise there.
Oh.
Total reputation!
Six!
But it's still here.
So there's nobody in here now, right?
Yeah, there's no...
Yeah, okay.
And I can't launch?
Nope.
Recover vessel.
Beautiful.
We got it all back.
Hey, I guess...
So if you get everything back, I guess you don't lose any money, right?
I mean, maybe you have to, you know, refurbish it a little bit.
SpaceX style.
Okay.
So now we should have this done, right?
Yeah!
This one didn't get completed because we died, and I had to revert.
That's why it's not counting.
Um...
Okay, let's...
Let's go again.
I'm gonna make the same one.
Oh!
I guess...
Wait a minute.
We could maybe use this.
As like a break, you know?
I don't know how simulated, like...
Air resistance is and all that.
But like, if we put this...
Maybe we can slow down more before parachute.
I mean, it sounds kinda dumb, obviously, but...
You know.
It is what it is.
This one!
Man, that is huge.
Uh...
Is there a way to sort of...
Toggle snap?
What's this?
Symmetry mode.
I am middle clicking.
Oh!
You wanna...
Oh wait, what?
Ah, okay, I see, I see.
Ah, cool.
Oh, much...
I...
I love that there's a snapping function.
I was looking for that.
Now it's like, yeah.
I like the snap.
I'm a snapper.
Now we're just one.
But I guess at all times you wanna, like, balance.
Right?
Otherwise...
Uh, center of mass is gonna be all messed up.
Actually, hold on.
Is it actually...
Changing?
Oh, you can see it move in real time before I even place it.
Look!
That's cool.
Ah, alright.
Neat.
But I don't know if I wanna do this.
Like, we need...
We actually don't have a mission for this.
So we just need to, uh, launch the vessel, really.
Uh, we need this.
Okay, let me actually see here.
Maybe we set this to...
5,000?
Maybe?
I don't know.
Put it at 5,000.
Uh...
Crew...
Jebediah is already in.
Great.
Get that away from me.
Also, I want this color again.
Actually, I like this one now.
Uniform!
Um...
I need to see something.
More info.
Semi deployed effective diameter, 0.8.
Fully deployed effective diameter, 20.7.
Max safe deploy speed at home.
Approximately 264 meters per second.
Full deployment attitude at 1,000.
Okay, so wait, if I change it...
Oh, I already did change it, so why...
Wait.
Maybe this is just like the default.
Right now it is at 1,000, but I can change it to...
Fully deploy at 5,000.
Uh, yeah.
Let me just keep it at 5,000.
So we want to slow down, obviously.
Yeah, let's just take a parabolic arc.
I think this is all I need.
If you think about it.
More air to go through.
Okay, so I have to be careful here now.
Whoa, oh, okay.
I actually don't have full authority here, because, you know...
Drag.
We should already be on a...
We're gonna land in the ocean.
Oh, wait.
Oh, it's actually showing here.
Look.
It's red.
Maybe I clicked when I was red.
Because we're too fast.
I'm gonna wait and click until we are...
Now.
Yep, last time it didn't deploy immediately when I clicked.
Remember?
Beautiful.
Oh, we're actually going way farther than I thought.
Oh, that's so cool, actually.
Um, I can also speed up.
Uh, warning.
Using physics warp can affect the structural stability of the vessel.
Be careful using it with large ships.
Okay.
Maybe I shouldn't do that.
I mean, it's not a large ship.
This is a very tiny one.
I think we're okay.
How far can I go?
4x, okay.
I don't wanna go too fast.
I don't wanna miss anything.
Uh-oh, uh-oh!
Uh-oh, speed!
Speed, speed, speed, speed, speed!
Can we somehow...
Go sideways?
More drag?
Oh, God.
I'm holding the button.
Uh, this...
No!
Oh, God.
Oh, we're slowing.
We're slowing down.
We're slowing down!
Am I actually helping?
If I let go, what then?
I guess the weight is concentrated in the front.
Yeah, I guess all the fuel is gone, right?
Hey!
Look at that!
That's...
That's beautiful.
We did it!
Look how excited he is!
Wonderful.
Okay, we can speed this up.
Damn, this looks cool.
Very nice.
Ooh, the moon!
Moon!
Can I see other...
From here?
It's probably too bright right now.
Dude, we're gonna be landing on the moon.
Today!
I just need to get the parts for it, you know?
I can do it.
Can I really not speed this up any faster?
That's crazy.
Oh!
Wait a minute!
Oh, okay, okay, okay.
So I didn't even pay attention.
I think the parachute actually did deploy at 5,000.
Because look, we're at 2,500 now, and it's been a while.
So if I had deployed it at...
1,000, we wouldn't have...
had to wait as long, I guess.
So next time I should just put it at 1,000.
But hey, now I know how that works.
And I guess you can either choose to adjust the altitude at which you want the...
parachute to deploy, or the pressure, you know?
There was also a pressure setting.
So the pressure setting, I guess, is gonna be...
invariant of the planet that you're on.
Or the, you know, celestial body.
It's just gonna measure whatever the...
I don't even know if I can see that from here.
Maybe I can...
Cut parachute?!
You can do that?!
That's crazy.
I'm not gonna do that, though.
Oh, we're gonna die if I do that!
Okay, faster, come on.
What's this?
Oh, I joined my stats.
Launch vessel achieved.
No more solid fuel.
Monopropellant and electric charge.
Okay.
Well, that was a long and beautiful descent.
I'm actually gonna go in here and look out the window.
Look how pretty that is.
It's a cloud.
It's moving quite fast because I have...
X4 speed on.
Kinda wish I could...
Wait, are we upside down right now?
We shouldn't be.
I actually wonder how he is aligned in there.
I guess if it's facing that way...
Okay, yeah.
Upside down.
What it looks like, at least.
Here we go!
The first successful landing.
That's amazing!
I kinda wanna try and go EVA, but I also kinda don't.
I feel like we should, uh, you know...
Take... take the win.
There we go, baby.
Cheers.
Recovery of a vessel that survived the flight!
We gained some science.
And...
Jebediah Kerman gained XP.
What does that do, though?
More reputation gained.
Um...
We have 16 science.
16 times the research.
Oh, we can actually get things.
Decouplers.
Too hot thermometer.
What does this cost?
18.
Okay, I can't even afford that.
And I guess you need to get it in sequence here, anyway.
Okay, I gotta go take a pistol quick, and then we're gonna unlock some more parts.
I'll be right back.
Okay.
I have decided something.
I'm actually not gonna unlock this yet.
Because...
I can already see myself getting overwhelmed.
So what we're gonna do...
We're gonna try all the parts before we unlock new parts.
We need to understand everything before we move on.
Like, I wanna know what this is used for.
For example.
Um...
So we're gonna take this...
Get rid of it.
Give me that one.
Wait, what?
Ah, okay.
Uh, and then with this...
Let me see here.
Crew.
Okay, so Jebediah is in.
There's also something else I had.
Uh...
I actually have an idea.
Look, it's an alien with antennas.
That's so dumb.
If I...
I wonder if I can go straight down now.
Since I have...
Actually, I could also...
Let me make...
Oh, it is already...
Surely this will go well.
Wait, wait.
How much does this cost?
Uh...
Oh.
1285.
I have to remember money here.
Oh, wait.
I have 122,000?
I thought I had 12,000.
Dude, I'm rich all of a sudden.
I can totally afford to just...
Do shit.
This one.
Just one.
Ah, but wait a minute.
Uh...
Okay, I thought it couldn't fit.
It didn't look like it would fit.
Wait, can I have multiple?
Wait a minute.
You can probably calculate how much you would...
Need here.
For this vessel.
Also, just adding more boosters like this is not necessarily gonna get us higher.
Because think about it.
We also weigh more, right?
So...
There's definitely a sweet spot you wanna hit with that.
Uh, if you think of the rocket equation...
It's a differential equation, right?
Because things change as you go along.
The weight itself changes.
Which means the thrust to weight ratio changes.
I think I got everything that I didn't try yet.
So, does this actually help me at all?
Let me actually just put these on here.
Wait, how does this work then if I...
Oh, okay, so they're being mirrored...
Or symmetrized...
Symmetrized...
Around...
The center of mass here.
I mean, sure.
Haha, this is so ugly!
Fuck me!
It's disgusting looking.
Wait, what is that?
What does that do?
Uh, force percent...
Wait a minute.
Just launch!
It's fine.
We can revert.
Just trial and error this.
Haha, Gemidile doesn't look too...
Comfortable with the situation.
Let me actually have a look inside.
Oh!
Fancy.
Whoa!
Cool!
You get to look across the ground there.
That's kind of neat.
Tape recorder.
Very good.
Uh, so let me see here.
So, all of these are going to be activated at the same time.
Then this will be activated.
Oh, is this...
I wonder if this is like a, um...
A separator.
It kind of looks like this will sort of pop off.
You know, like this thing.
Like that.
And then all these should activate at the same time.
Ah, but wait a minute.
Wait a second.
If this pops off...
Then these are gone anyway.
And it doesn't matter.
Ah, fuck it.
Let's just launch.
Uh...
Oh my fucking god.
Control!
Control it!
Oh shit!
What's happening?
Oh god.
Fucking...
Yo, that's cool!
Oh, rip.
Oh, I guess this one is meant to, uh...
Fall down in the ocean, right?
Ah, that's neat.
You see how it popped off?
Like I said it would.
Beautiful.
That was so cool.
Let's get down to the floor.
Don't worry, Jebediah.
We're just testing things.
Oh, wait a second!
I also put something else on it I wanted to test.
Too late for that, I guess.
Crew report.
Crew report from Kerbin Shores.
You record the crew's assessment of the situation.
Yes.
What is the assessment of the situation?
What happens if I...
It says 100% science value.
No usable in-range comms devices.
Lights on.
Oh, inside!
You see how he's lit?
Crew report.
Transfer crew.
Select the part to transfer Jebediah Kerman to.
What is the source part?
Okay, I'm just- I'm just clicking things here.
I'm going super slow in this game on purpose, by the way.
Because I don't want to miss anything and I want to make sure I understand before I move on, you know?
Wait, what?
Interior overlay?
Oh, it's grass.
Nice.
Well, shit.
Recover vessel.
I mean, we keep getting science.
We have 18 now.
Very nice.
Okay, I'm gonna...
What is the...
Okay.
So I can just do the same one if I want.
Edit vessel.
This vessel sucks, bro.
This is a horrible design.
I'm actually ashamed.
Can I just delete?
Can.
Okay, so we're gonna...
Actually, hold on.
I wonder...
Do we even need to launch at all?
We're gonna save money, right?
So what I'm gonna do...
How do I just...
Do that one.
Go to that one.
Um...
Put this here.
Deploy?
Wait, what?
Oh, hold on.
I guess you wanna...
Open that?
When you're flying?
Or...
Wait a minute.
EVA.
So, can you actually just not get back up, or...
I had the prompt just briefly.
You saw that?
Observe Mystery Goo.
Mystery Goo observation can only be externally controlled by a scientist.
Oh, I have one of those.
But externally controlled?
Climb.
Bro, I don't understand how to get back in the vehicle.
This is very confusing for me.
Climb!
I saw the prompt.
Climb back in, you bastard.
I'm gonna be ready to click.
This is very gimmicky, or like...
Janky.
I don't know how this works, bro.
Inventory.
Space center.
Hmm.
And then I guess we recover?
Okay.
Recover.
Jesus Christ.
Okay, wait a minute.
It said externally.
So, what if I do it internally?
Now I'm inside.
Observe Mystery Goo.
Hey!
Mystery Goo observation from Launchpad.
The goo doesn't seem to be doing much right now.
2.7 science.
Oh, transmitting is only 42% of the original value.
Okay.
Decouple?
Wait, we gotta try.
Oh.
Alright.
Crew report.
Crew report from Launchpad.
You'll record the crew's assessment of the situation.
Uh, okay.
And now we have more science.
Look at that!
We're at 22 now!
I think we needed 18 to get the next stage of science stuff.
Uh, okay, I'm gonna unlock more stuff now.
Now that we have fully understood everything we got.
Uh, the question is, do we go into Basic Rocketry, or Engineering 101?
So this one has a TD-12 decoupler.
The TD-12 stack decoupler is equipped with a hopefully small explosive charge, that will sever the structural linkage between itself and whatever it's connected to.
Painted on its sides are handy arrows indicating which sides will detach.
Right.
So this is what you need for staging rockets.
Too Hot Thermometer.
This thermometer is definitely not a store-bought model with some wire stuck to it.
Are you sure about that?
Warranty void if an engineer admits it's actually a store-bought model with some wire stuck to it.
Hmm.
Communitron.
The Communitron-16 is a versatile and lightweight antenna, suitable for moderate-range communication.
Long-range backup communication and eavesdropping on secret government operations.
And then this one.
Communitron-16s.
What's the difference other than the looks?
This one weighs a bit more.
Okay.
Oh, wait, there's more.
Data transmitter.
Antenor rating 500k.
What the fuck is this even...
Like the amount of data you can transfer per second or something?
Oh, bandwidth.
Mids per second.
Oh, yeah, okay.
Packet size is the same.
Versus L1-DSN.
Hmm.
I guess it's just looks, maybe?
Then we have these parts.
So obviously we want a liquid fuel engine.
We're gonna take this.
Hammer solid fuel booster.
And a fuel tank.
I think it's obvious we gotta go for this one.
Purchase three parts.
Oh, we have to buy them.
Okay.
Not even that expensive.
Thrust ASL 167kN.
In vacuum it's obviously more.
This one is stronger.
But it's also a solid booster so you can't turn it off.
That's the difference between these.
That's why you want...
That's why the...
Space Shuttle has massive...
Or had, I guess.
Massive solid boosters on the sides.
And then they just dispose of those when they're done, right?
You turn them on like a candle.
And they just go.
Okay.
I may actually...
Okay, I can't actually afford this.
This is 20.
I thought they were all gonna be the same here.
Survivability.
Okay, okay.
I'm not actually gonna look at that.
I can't afford it yet.
I'm gonna buy this.
Yeah, dude.
Let's go make something new.
Oh, actually!
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
I need to leave.
We gotta check missions.
Holy shit!
Look at all this!
Conduct a focused observational survey of Kerbin.
Okay.
While working late nights, the scientists at Ionic Symphonic Protonic Electronics have made a startling discovery.
We don't know too many interesting things about Kerbin, and would like to take a look around.
This is why we're here.
We need to test our newly acquired capabilities with a focused survey of Kerbin.
Go to the designated test site and gather some observational reports.
Okay.
Take a crew report in flight above 19,200 meters near Bilemini's Greatness.
This is the same thing, but it's like a different place.
I wonder if these are all, like, randomly generated.
This feels randomly generated.
I could be wrong.
It feels like that.
Test parachute and flight over Kerbin.
While cleaning up after an unintended ignition, one of the overworked teams at Freefall Parachutes raised an interesting question.
There is very little knowledge about how the MK-16 parachute performs under conditions not found in a standard laboratory.
We believe that you are much better positioned to deal with this than us.
We want you to test the parachute and flight over Kerbin.
So this one is trivial.
Oh, these are all trivial.
Um...
Wait, duration one year?
What do you mean?
Wait, what do you mean?
Oh, the offer expires in two days, but I guess I can complete it in one year.
Which is kind of nuts.
That's a long time.
Alright.
To perform the test, activate the part through the staging sequence when all the test conditions are met.
We test the parachute.
Kerbin flying between a thousand and six thousand.
Oh my god, that is...
That is, like, so specific.
Jesus.
Test TD-12 decoupler splashdown at Kerbin.
Now that sounds more manageable.
The CEO and chief bottle washer at OMB Demolition Enterprises has stumbled on a problem.
There is very little knowledge about how the TD-12 decoupler performs under conditions not found in a standard laboratory.
Okay.
So we have to test this while on Kerbin and splashdown.
Dude, these missions are weird, man.
See, this is what I can get behind.
Escape the atmosphere!
That makes sense.
Test liquid fuel engine on an escape trajectory out of Kerbin.
I don't even know what the escape velocity is of Kerbin.
Feels like a lot.
Completion is 50,000 credits.
Eight signs only for that.
I feel like we should escape the atmosphere.
Isn't that the next logical step here?
Maybe orbiting is a little too crazy right now.
We definitely need more fuel for that.
We can try one of these.
Conduct a focused observational survey of Kerbin.
Okay, so we gotta go...
to 19...
19,200 meters.
Oh, just above that.
Okay.
Near Belimony's Greatness.
I guess it's gonna show me where?
And then we cannot have any more.
Okay, let's see.
Contracts.
Take a crew report in flight.
Can I somehow...
see a map?
I'm pretty sure that was a map.
Like, not the tracking station.
Is it just...
Oh!
I think this is it.
Wait, wait a minute.
Belimony's Greatness.
Okay, so it's like west of here.
Assuming this is north.
But wait, that's like kinda crazy, isn't it?
I can barely fly a rocket.
Wait a minute, how do I know, uh...
Can I...
somehow...
target that, or...
Hmm...
Confusing.
Maybe just need to launch, and then it'll tell me.
Okay, fuck this stupid-ass craft.
Get it out of my face!
We're making something great now.
Actually, hold on.
We should really test all the new stuff here.
So we got a fuel tank now.
Uh...
And this one is...
liquid fuel.
That's gonna work with this liquid fuel engine.
This is just a bigger version of, uh...
the flea.
Yeah.
Like twice.
Now that's what I'm talking about, baby!
That's what we need.
Uh...
And then we also got some new stuff here, somewhere.
This one.
TD-12 decoupler.
Ooh, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Actually...
Yo!
We are gonna make a staged rocket right now!
Uh...
First, we need this.
I'm gonna change the color.
Uh...
Then we're gonna need...
Parachute.
Oh!
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
We're gonna do this.
Right?
So at the end...
It's just these.
And then we're gonna do...
Now...
Now comes the liquid fuel engine.
We're gonna just stack these.
I don't know how many I need.
Let's say three.
Can I change the color?
Nice.
Ah, I don't actually like how that looks.
Maybe I can...
Okay, that's cool.
I like that.
Uh...
Then we're gonna need one of these.
Oh, man.
Oh, no.
So...
And I can just keep going with this.
Oh, sweet!
Jesus.
So check it out.
The rocket's gonna use this first.
We're gonna decouple when it's empty.
It's weight that we don't need anymore.
Boom.
Gone.
This falls in the ocean.
Now we activate this stage.
And we go...
Uh...
Because this one has more control, I guess.
We can actually turn it off and on, right?
Um...
And then...
There was something else.
This...
Oh, yeah.
Oh, wait.
Why is it not snapping?
Oh, that's annoying.
I want it to be perfectly aligned.
Then again.
Is that gonna be weird?
If it's like the parachute.
This is gonna open, right?
That's not a good idea.
Oh, actually, um...
Let me see this one.
Oh, that's better.
Then I need to...
If I can rotate that, that would be fantastic.
Actually, we can just...
Hmm...
Do we even need this?
I guess if we wanna send some...
But...
We're planning to come back, right?
That's why we have the parachute.
We don't need this.
Thermometer!
Zoom in.
It's kinda silly though, just...
Putting thermometer on the front of the spacecraft.
Store-bought thermometer.
I doubt this is gonna survive...
Anything.
But, uh...
Alright.
Sure.
We can do that.
Cargo.
I feel like I unlocked way more, didn't I?
Is this really it?
It's like a bunch of shit I unlocked.
Okay, so hold on.
We turn this on first.
Detach.
Gone.
Wait, what does this mean?
What is the...
Oh, is that this?
Oh, okay, okay.
I see.
So then this goes on.
And...
It's empty.
What then?
Detach.
In the ocean.
This is left.
Parachute.
Bob's your uncle.
This is fantastic.
Okay.
Are we ready?
Oh, we gotta name this.
I feel like the others were not really counting.
This is going to be, uh...
Mmm...
Let's call it, uh...
Importance.
The first...
Actual...
Real...
Deal rocket.
The other ones were kinda bullshit.
This one is the real deal.
You know?
Launch.
Cheers, guys!
Oh, man.
It actually looks super cool already.
I like the way this looks.
Oh...
Okay.
Here we go.
We're gonna go in an arc.
We're gonna turn out towards the water.
Oh, it's doing it on its own.
I don't mind that.
That's...
That's good.
Oh, my God.
We're so aerodynamic, too.
Look at us.
Whoa.
Wait.
Why is it not...
No.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
No!
What the fuck?
You bastard!
That's not...
That's not what I wanted to do.
God damn it.
Whoa.
Okay.
That's very sensitive.
Holy crap.
Oh, my God.
Can we...
Other way.
Keep it here.
Oh, no.
Oh, shit.
Actually, we can...
We can deploy a parachute.
It's not red.
This should be fine.
Whee!
So pretty.
Look at that moon up there, man.
Taunting me.
Oh, that's so beautiful.
And look.
Look.
It deployed around a thousand this time.
Actually, hold on.
I want to see.
Ah.
It's never a good view from this pod here.
Kind of a terrible view.
I like that it actually has working, you know, indicators here.
Like, for example, the nav ball and this one.
I guess this means surface...
Uh...
Something...
Yeah.
Actually, surface.
I was trying to figure out what the acronym was, but it's actually just a shortened word.
Surface.
It's the speed relative to the surface.
Beautiful.
Uh...
Okay.
So...
Wait.
What about the thermometer?
Toggle display.
Ah.
You displayed in kelvins?
That's crazy, bro.
I don't even...
Ah.
What is that?
That is like...
Uh...
73.
That's like...
That's like 7...
20...
29-ish.
Celsius.
Hot day.
Log temperature.
Temperature scan while flying over Kerbin's water.
Collected and recorded temperature data from the environment.
That's five signs, baby.
Not bad.
Kinda wanna go EVA right now.
Um...
Should I do it?
I mean, we can always revert.
Oh!
Oh my god.
I thought he was gonna drown.
Haha!
EVA report.
EVA report from Kerbin's water.
Oh!
Actually, I shouldn't do that.
Wait.
Remove neck ring?
Oh!
Right.
This reminds me of, um...
The movie, uh...
Wild Wild West with Will Smith.
You know, they have those...
Metal things around their necks.
And there's...
Okay, you're actually gonna drown.
Uh...
Put the helmet on.
Wait!
Store experiments!
Wait, whoa!
What's happened?
EVA report from...
Excuse me.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Actually, we can just climb up here.
Whoa.
The waters are unruly.
I don't know.
I didn't get to read that.
But, uh...
We stored something.
Take data.
Oh, so I...
I guess I can do multiple EVA reports.
Recover vet...
Recover vessel.
Wait a minute.
I'm an idiot.
I didn't even do the thing I wanted to do.
I actually...
I wanted to...
Do the missions I had.
But hey, we got eight science.
And we recovered all these parts.
Everything went actually super smooth.
This was...
This was great.
We staged the rockets...
Beautifully.
Actually, hold on.
We kinda fucked up.
The second stage, uh...
Didn't turn on.
And...
Me thinks, actually, it's because we didn't...
Turn it on.
Meaning we didn't act...
Because we...
You can control that, right?
Uh...
I'm gonna...
Save the game.
I'm gonna go to the menu.
We're gonna look at the input again.
Because, apparently, you cannot look at the frickin' hotkeys while you're in the game.
Which is, like, insane.
Vessel.
Full throttle.
Throttle cut off.
S-A-S hold.
Okay.
Let me just see what else...
Actually, I should write some of this down.
Uh...
Wait a minute.
Okay.
What is, like, super important here?
I guess we...
Oh!
Roll left...
And roll right.
Okay, so we can do that.
Q and E, that makes sense.
Translate...
Up and down.
Okay, so...
Okay...
Let's not...
Throttle!
Left...
Okay, control and shift.
That's easy.
Switch translation.
Precision controls toggle.
Caps lock!
Ooh!
I think I need to know that one.
I was flying all over the place just now.
Okay.
Brakes is...
Brakes?
I guess if you have wheels.
Kerbals.
Grab is F.
Yeah.
Board is B.
Toggle movement mode.
I don't know what that means.
Oh, we...
Oh, there's actually, uh...
Keybinds for this, for the helmets too.
Interesting.
Toggle EVA construction mode?
What does it mean?
Orbital map view!
I tried clicking M!
But maybe you can only do it in certain situations.
It's like my go-to for maps and games, you know, M.
Yeah.
Double mouse look...
Wait a minute.
Guys, Rotund, is there a way to see these keybinds while playing?
Do I actually need to go to the menu every time?
Because I'm losing my mind right now.
I'm asking.
There is?
How?
My bad.
How do I see it?
Take...
Take screenshots?
Wait, so I can't?
Oh, you mean yes, as in I can't do it.
Oh man, what?
That's crazy.
Oh man.
Okay, okay.
Thank you guys.
I just had to, you know...
Get a, uh...
What do you call it?
Sanity check there on that.
It seemed too crazy to me, not being able to do that.
But okay.
That's fine.
Okay, we go back in.
I need to launch rockets, man.
So we use, uh...
Z?
Or Zed?
I don't know what actually is the right thing to say in...
In the American language.
For max throttle, and you also have shift and control.
Uh...
Importance!
We're gonna...
We're gonna launch this again.
We're gonna do it again.
Hells yeah.
Actually, what we're gonna do first...
Lock temperature.
Look!
From launch pad now.
Looks like you can have all these different conditions.
And it's gonna be different.
Keep experiment.
In fact, uh...
Crew report.
Zero.
Why?
But I kept it.
So what does that mean?
Wait.
Uh...
Review report.
Maybe it's because I already...
Did it...
I think I did this before.
And it's...
You don't get anything out of it to do again.
Otherwise, that would kind of be, you know, crazy.
That would make sense.
Okay.
Um...
Maybe we can do...
EVA?
Don't fall down!
Oh my god, the rocket is so tiny when you look at it from this perspective.
Uh...
EVA report.
Also zero.
Okay, so we don't get anything from that.
Reset experiment.
Okay.
Are we ready?
Um...
There we go, look at that!
Max speed.
I think I just want to keep it at max, actually.
Okay, let me just confirm.
So this one.
That one.
That one, that one.
Hey, we could also...
Do this?
Then it's gonna happen at the same time.
I think.
Here we go!
Uh...
Freaking, uh...
Space rocket blasting off once again.
Or whatever.
They say in Digimon.
Digital monsters.
Da da da da da da.
I don't...
I don't actually watch that, but I know that's like a thing.
Okay, so get ready.
Solid fuel is running out now.
Yeah, baby!
Oh shit.
Oh wait, fine control?
Oh, much better.
Uh oh, wait a minute.
Whoa, we're going fast.
And that's that.
Detach!
Oh my god.
Oh!
Uh, thermometer!
It's hot!
Yes.
Temperature scan from Kerbin's upper atmosphere.
Collected and recorded temperature data from the environment.
Six and a half.
Hey, look at my booster go.
Hey!
Look at this!
80 kilometers!
That's crazy.
Um...
Crew report.
Crew report while in space near Kerbin.
Keep it.
Oh, I should have brought the goo, actually, for this.
It's probably like...
I mean, we're just falling right now.
So...
We should be...
Weightless, right?
So the goo would be all over.
Cannot disembark while off of Kerbin's surface.
Astronaut complex upgrade required!
What?!
I can't spacewalk right now!
I was hoping to do that.
Oh my god, bro.
We are...
Wait, how far up?
I need to...
Yeah!
There we go.
That's a parabola, alright.
Oh, wait a minute.
That's the thing we need to get to.
Belimini's greatness.
What is that line?
Well, we're gonna...
We're gonna...
Crash in the ocean.
That's fine, though.
I'm happy with that.
I like this music.
The Milky Way.
Beautiful.
I gotta say, man, the game runs really well.
Like...
When this game first came out, it ran like shit.
But I also had a terrible computer back then.
You know?
700 meters per second right now.
That is so fast.
That's beautiful.
Look at the stars.
It's full of stars.
They're alive.
Dude, I'm gonna be loving this view, I think.
Throughout the game.
I wish you could kinda control it from here.
That would be kinda dope.
Like, I wanna...
Oh!
You can control it from here!
Why...
I couldn't click anything else, though.
What the hell?
Okay, so I guess that's the one I can.
Interesting.
Huh.
Wait, I wonder.
Ah!
That is the throttle!
Cool.
I'm using shift now.
Sweet.
I mean, there's nothing to throttle right now.
You know?
Let's see here.
Are we actually on our way down?
Not yet.
I guess we can fast forward a little bit.
Wow.
Wait a minute.
We're coming down at a very steep angle here.
Ooh!
Are we gonna be too fast?
If anything, we wanna point our, uh, capsule...
Along the...
Uh...
We...
Like, we wanna point the bottom along the trajectory, right?
Wait, what is...
Oh, it's so sensitive.
Hold on.
Whoa!
Okay, now...
I was in precision mode.
Now it's super sensitive.
What is that one?
Dude, it's so fast...
It's like inverted.
When you click down, it goes up, you know?
Would be...
I wonder if I can connect the joystick to this and actually...
Control it like that.
That would be kinda dope, actually.
Cause I have a joystick.
Which way am I falling?
I'm falling that way.
We wanna be pointing it this way.
Oh, maybe that's what that is, actually.
It's the direction we're moving.
Whoops.
Sometimes, like, the camera gets stuck in, like, the view mode.
And I have to right-click to get out of it.
I don't know how I'm doing that.
But not when I...
Hold right-click, it doesn't.
Like, it...
When I let go, it, you know, goes back.
So, I don't know.
I'm scared.
Let's speed up a little bit.
Whoa.
Jebediah!
It's gonna be alright.
We're coming down hot here.
I'm sorry I didn't give you a shallow angle.
Jebediah is excited though.
I mean, look at his face.
That's great.
What is all this?
Docking mode.
Yo!
We're gonna dock...
...at some point.
Oh!
Is that happening?
Wow, is that the transition?
Just cuts off?
I mean, we are...
We are moving very, very, very fast right now.
Oh!
Here we go!
We're entering the atmosphere.
Oh, shit.
Uh-oh.
Uh...
What's that sound?
Whoa, what the fuck?
What was that?
Oh!
We're slowing down.
Parachute?
I think that was close!
We should be okay now.
We're slowing down.
Beautiful.
And the best part is...
We got the science, baby.
Oh, yeah.
Where's the moon?
What's that?
Something back there.
Beautiful.
Man, what a landing, huh?
Sunset and everything.
Tell me that isn't amazing.
Oh, yeah.
You're probably feeling sick.
Sitting upside down like that.
Why did they make you sit upside down?
That's horrible.
My stomach is growling, even though I'm not hungry.
What is wrong with you, stomach?
I fed you already.
It's like a little food demon that is inside of me.
That always wants more.
Oh!
Look at that.
Dude.
That's beautiful.
We are gonna...
Wait, how are we gonna get picked up?
We are just in the middle of nowhere.
Oh, God.
EVA report.
From Kerbin's Water.
Oh, no science!
I thought for sure maybe we would get something new here, but okay.
Reset.
Alrighty.
What about crew report?
Overwrite?
Wait.
Review.
No, we have crew report while in space.
We're gonna keep that one for sure.
Oh!
Wait a minute.
Oh, this is so much better.
We're gonna adjust this as we go along.
It was so sensitive.
We just put down the wheel authority.
Much better.
Okay, recover the vessel.
Successful mission.
We are on our way to greatness.
Look at that.
18.2 science.
And we have 51 science, baby!
Holy shit!
Let me see the...
Oh, we...
I guess we...
I guess we did enter, uh...
or leave the atmosphere.
I wish it would kind of show up as like a...
Ta-da!
You completed the mission, you know?
Because it just happens in the back, it seems.
Uh...
We need another one.
Actually, we have one.
This one.
Let's try and see if we can figure this one out.
So we have to go to this place.
And I...
Yeah, I cannot open the map while I'm here.
I can only do that while I'm flying.
Okay.
Whoops!
I didn't mean to click that, but that's fine.
The question is...
Honestly, I think we can easily get into orbit with this.
Like, we just add more thrusters.
Or maybe even another stage.
You know?
Uh...
Fuel tank.
There's a sweet spot, of course.
You don't want to add too many fuel tanks either.
Otherwise, you can't get off the ground.
So, there's that.
Uh...
And I guess this will help me with authority, if I need it.
But I don't need it right now.
I think we should go unlock more science stuff.
Let's do it.
I have 50 science.
Okay, so...
This looks to be, like, rocket-focused.
Uh...
Yeah, okay.
I guess there is kind of a category.
Yeah.
Oh, this...
This is the path of rockets here.
This is the path of general...
Advanced construction.
Specialized construction.
What does that say?
160!
Damn.
That's a lot.
Um...
General rocketry.
So, what do we get here?
Another fuel engine.
I'm guessing it's stronger?
205, 240.
Yep.
It is stronger.
So, it's just better.
1.25 tons.
And this one...
Yeah, it's lighter and faster.
That's crazy.
So, just straight up upgrade.
Back thumper solid fuel booster.
Now, this is what I'm talking about.
This looks like, um...
The sort of fuel booster that you would put on the space shuttle.
You know, on the sides.
Another fuel tank.
Um...
I am inclined to take this, but let's see.
Aerodynamic nose cone.
Winglet.
Radial decoupler.
So, basically, space shuttle.
And here there's a lot.
Heat shield!
I think we may need to go this way.
Press mat barometer.
A device for measuring the local atmospheric pressure.
Warranty void if exposed to air.
Ha ha ha!
Well, shit.
Radiator panel.
Wait, what's the point of this?
A radiator...
A radially...
Radially attachable radiator panel to help dissipate heat into space.
Wait a second.
Are you saying there's actually a system where you have to manage the heat inside a spacecraft?
In space?
That's cool!
Landing struts.
Uh...
Service bays.
A heat-resistant service bay.
Ideal for protecting delicate instruments or stowing small service components such as RCS tanks, batteries.
Okay.
Well, we can get two of these.
And I am...
I'm thinking this one is boring.
Dude, there's a lot.
Look at all this.
This one seems the most boring.
I want this.
I want a...
Thick booster, you know?
A chonky boy.
And then I want this.
Actually, wait a minute.
Oh, it's 45.
Dang.
Also, we shouldn't unlock too much.
We're gonna unlock these two.
Yeah.
Take this one.
I want heat shield.
That seems to be a pressing concern, doesn't it?
Uh...
Let's see here.
Okay, we got new toys.
Is that just not the same, but bigger?
45?
90?
It's funny how they also have oxidizer there.
Like, are they actually simulating that, or...?
Because you need both to burn it, right?
I mean, in real life.
But I mean...
They could just have called it fuel.
You know what I mean?
So I wonder if there's actually specific systems with that.
So this one is lighter, and it's just better.
It even survives the same sort of temperatures.
It's also cheaper!
So why would I ever use this again?
Alright, we're definitely using the new one.
Let me actually read it.
Although criticized some due to their not insignificant use of so-called pieces found lying about, the LVT series engines have proven themselves as comparatively reliable.
I guess that's why it's called Reliant.
The T30 model boasts a failure and Radley bits ratio below the 50% mark.
This has been considered a major improvement over previous models by engineers and LVT enthusiasts.
Okay.
Oh wait, there's actually more.
Engine ISP.
Propellants.
This won't even burn- Okay, I guess it burns more per second.
So that makes sense, I guess.
Since you want more- Since you want more- Or since it does more- Uh, thrust, right?
Shroud, truss mount, bear.
Oh!
Oh, that's cool.
I kinda like where you can see the whole thing.
Oh, cool!
What is the shroud?
I'm confused about that.
I like that look, that's nice.
Okay.
And...
Damn!
Okay, this is now- Oh, wait a minute.
How do I actually- Do I have to attach it first?
I have such a weird system.
Look in the little phallic here!
You know what we need?
We need- We need- The little winglets.
These ones.
But like more.
Hahaha!
They're kinda small, aren't they?
So, this- This reminds me of, you know, the- The dinosaur, or the T-Rex with the tiny arms.
It- It has the same energy.
I don't know if this will actually help me at all.
Lifting surface, relative wing area, 0.12?
Is it just- It's not just flavor.
It's for sure doing something.
Whoa.
The camera just- Whoa, confused me.
Uh, okay, so let me see.
So we burn this.
Throw away.
Wait, I can't see-
Oh, okay, it's just kinda hidden.
Oh, is that what the- Ah!
But you definitely want the shroud while flying.
This is just for building.
Hmm.
Cool.
Now I can see it.
Oh, that's actually really nice.
And I guess- Hold on a minute.
We don't actually need these anymore.
Because we have a better one now.
Actually, does it even make a difference?
It- It's cheaper.
It's cheaper, that's why.
Oh, nice!
I like that!
Definite space shuttle energy.
Um...
There we go.
Okay, so we do this.
Oh god, hold on.
We do this.
So this one's gone.
In the ocean.
We burn this.
This one's gone.
In the ocean.
Actually, wait, wait.
Yeah, this one's gone.
And then this is left.
Beautiful.
Then we can cover this up.
Okay.
Uh, let me see what else we can do.
So, service bay.
Need to see this.
This is a cargo part that can be placed inside inventories.
Really?
You can put this in your pocket?
Ha!
What?
What do you mean?
I guess we...
It's supposed to go in between or something?
But why?
A deal for protecting delicate instruments or stowing small service components.
Oh.
Oh, that's cool.
So you want to put things in there.
Landing strut.
Oh, wait a minute.
Heat shield.
I mean, I don't want to do that.
But it's cool that you can.
Um...
I guess I want that here.
There we go.
When would you need this?
I'm trying to think.
Is it actually like...
Maybe there's like a system where if you're in the sun too much in space...
There's like a...
Maybe that's what the thermometer is also for.
Why you want to look at the...
Oh, but that's outside.
Like the kerbals inside are going to get cooked.
If there's not a ways to radiate heat away.
Right?
Wait, that looks wrong.
Oh!
Okay.
That looks a little goofy.
But alright.
So hold on.
Oh, wait, wait, wait.
Uh...
So now we have...
This one.
Uh...
We burn that.
Detach.
Gone.
We burn this.
Detach and all of this...
Is gone.
So now we have the heat shield on the capsule.
And...
Bob's your uncle.
That's it.
Put the shroud on.
Do I even want this service bay?
Oh, wait a minute.
Maybe I can put, uh...
Science things!
Oh god.
What?
Why does it look like that?
Huh?
Oh!
Okay.
I guess that's why.
It's clipping through!
Oh my god.
It's unplayable.
Can I not move it?
Oh, I can also put it on the sides.
What the...
There we go.
Beautifully aligned.
Look at that.
It almost looks like a little...
Reactor or something in there.
Haha.
So you hope...
What do you have in there?
Goo.
Why?
Just...
Because.
We brought goo.
It makes sense.
Just trust.
We're gonna close that.
Uh...
Oh wait!
Wait a minute.
We're gonna have to bring this back, aren't we?
This is gonna fall in the ocean.
We gotta...
We gotta do this.
There we go.
Fixed.
Now we can actually bring it home.
Uh...
But something seems wrong still.
This one.
Gone.
And now we have this with the parachute.
Okay.
Good.
Oh wait!
We can also put this in there.
I wonder if it's gonna matter though, because technically it's not on the outside anymore, so it's not gonna be able to take readings out there.
Let's figure it out.
Oh.
Yeah, I guess...
That works.
Hey!
Let's wait.
Okay, what else did we get?
We got something else that was new.
Radial mount drogue chutes.
The Mark 12R is a half-sized radial mount version of the Mark 25.
This drogue parachute is small, deploys high up, and certainly not enough to stop you smashing into the ground on its own, but useful for slowing craft down before the deployment of your main chutes.
Sweet!
Yo, that's cool.
Just like real life.
Do I even need this though?
Like, we were kinda chilling last time.
But I guess I wanna do it to try.
Maybe you want like three of these.
Isn't that what you usually see?
On the spacecraft when they come back, they have like three.
Oh no, it's covering the logo!
That can't... that can't be good.
Oh, we just put it higher up, I guess.
Or higher... further down.
Oh, we can also put it here.
Ah, but if you think about it...
Yeah, that could work, actually.
We can't put it on the...
Ah, we can't put it here, because that's where the doors open.
That's why.
That makes sense.
Let's just... let's use two then, because we can't do three.
Otherwise, they're gonna go on the doors that open.
Okay.
So, let me actually see these.
They deploy at 2500, okay.
For some reason, I expect these to deploy way higher up.
But, uh, alright.
And pressure is lower, of course, because higher up in the atmosphere.
Uh...
I wonder... if I change this...
Which one is it gonna use?
Like, which is the preferred one?
You know?
Is it gonna prefer the pressure first?
Like, prioritize, I mean?
Also, maybe there's a way to...
Oh!
There is a way.
I was about to say, can we measure pressure?
But here it is!
Barometer, right?
We should bring that too!
We're going on a trip!
Oh, it's kinda...
Big.
I thought this would be, like, super small.
Oh god, it is...
It feels really janky, man.
That's amazing.
Look at that!
Okay.
Now we have one of each.
This is all science.
Let's bring one of these.
We don't want to be cooking...
Oh, that's a big one!
Ah, wait a minute.
Is that good?
This is gonna add...
This is not, like...
Hmm.
I don't know about that.
I feel like that's a bad idea.
It doesn't look aerodynamic.
Like, it's gonna mess up things.
I wonder what's gonna go in robotics.
Really curious about that.
Okay, well...
I think we're ready.
Close that.
That's...
Also, what am I even doing?
We have to take a crew report in flight above...
That place.
How the fuck am I gonna do that?
Like...
I mean, honestly, right now I'm kinda...
I wanna...
This is the, um...
Very...
Or...
What should we call this one?
I feel like it's still in the...
Importance class of rockets, you know?
Importance...
Science...
Edition, you know?
We go...
On a trip...
And...
We let it rip.
Save.
Last check.
Ah, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
We wanna deploy these further up, so we wanna do this.
Why are there three?
Did I put three?
What have I done?
Two.
There we go.
I think I...
I think the last one must have, like, gotten clipped in the geometry or something.
Okay, dude, we're re...
Actually, hold on.
I was thinking...
If we have it up here instead...
Think about the angle we come in at, you know?
I'm just thinking logically now.
Uh...
Let me show you.
If this is the heat shield...
The heat is gonna go off like that, you know?
If it's, like, out here, it's gonna hit that.
I don't know if they simulated that, but this feels more safe, you know?
It's like being behind a hill when a big wave is coming.
Or, like, when an explosion is there.
You wanna go in the little hole in the ground.
You know what I mean by that?
Uh...
Alright, man!
We have a big rocket here.
Save it.
Launch.
Here we go!
So pretty.
Okay, um...
So...
Let me actually see something.
Oh!
Oh yeah, right, I guess it's up in the air.
Activate navigation!
Oh!
That was easy.
So, basically, we have to...
Aim that way.
What's this?
Oh, map filters?
So we just turn left?
Or west?
Is that actually west?
No, this is...
Oh, this is...
Oh, this is south, uh...
That way, south.
This is north.
Man, why'd they do it like that?
Why is the default view that this is north?
That's confusing me.
So I guess we're going...
Uh, east.
Now.
But...
To me, it's always gonna be...
I'm probably gonna mess that up.
Because, you know, in my mind.
Uh...
I look at this...
Ball here, and I'm like...
Okay, that's definitely west.
Here we go.
So...
Wait, stop, stop.
Uh...
I need to...
Nineteen...
Nineteen thousand two hundred.
Okay.
I guess we can slowly start turning that way.
Oh my god.
It's beautiful.
Beautiful.
Let's...
Okay.
Oh, we're actually going...
We're going fast now.
Uh...
Left, left, left.
I can't turn anymore.
It's like stuck.
Oh shit.
Oh shit, I forgot to activate!
The thing.
Oh!
We just need it to be higher, right?
We just need it to be higher.
Hold on.
Slow down a bit.
Turn off.
Fuck!
What was it?
Uh...
Take a crew report in flight.
We're entering Belemonie's greatness.
Upper atmosphere.
Yeah!
And now...
For my next trick!
Oh, so this is like the...
I see.
The current, uh...
Vector.
We're going back up, baby.
Actually, uh...
Oh, I ran out of fuel.
Well, there we go.
That's all I could do.
Ha!
We're actually gonna land on land.
Beautiful.
Or maybe not, actually.
I guess we'll see.
Um, I need to check something.
So now we have that.
Oh my god.
This is so cool.
Open this.
Ha-ho!
I wish I could see the goo!
The goo seems to have clumped into a sphere!
It also appears to have become brittle.
Nine signs for that one.
In space near Kerbin.
Dude, look!
It kinda looks like a proper...
Aircraft.
Or not aircraft, but like...
Rocket ship, doesn't it?
Like, look at this.
The way they're sort of strutting out there.
It kinda looks like that, doesn't it?
I think it looks hella cool.
In fact, I wanna look at the Earth.
I mean, Kerbin.
How cold is it?
In vacuum!
Ha-ha-ha-ha!
So...
Pretty cold.
Atmospheric pressure scan while in space near Kerbin.
The instrument reads zero!
It's as if it were in a vacuum.
That's crazy!
I can't believe it!
That's a lot of science.
317 Kelvin.
Wait, what?
That's really hot.
I guess it's because of the sun.
I wonder!
If we actually were on the other side of the planet, if that would've gone down, like...
I guess they must be simulating this, because...
Why else would they have these radiator panels?
You know?
Okay, space near Kerbin.
Collected and recorded temperature data.
Oh my god!
Cheers!
Look at that!
That's beautiful.
Can you even see the Milky Way in the back there?
Oh, what is that?!
Wait, is that...
Is that my other stage?
What is that back there?
Look at that!
No, I don't know what that is.
Huh.
I have no idea what that is.
We have reached the top of the parabola.
Uh, what's it called when you're, um...
We're in a suborbital flight right now.
Actually, we seem to be hitting, uh...
Water now.
The trajectory has changed slightly.
Hell of a rescue operation.
We're gonna have to coordinate with the other countries on Kerbin.
To collect this bad boy.
So, what does this mean?
It's pointing...
Towards there.
Whoa.
This one...
It's like...
Oh!
Tangent?
To the planet, I guess?
This one is opposite...
Of where I'm pointing.
So if I turn this around...
Yeah.
It's like the X, you know?
It's like an arrow.
You see the...
What do you call it?
The stabilizer...
Of the arrow.
Oh, uh...
Wait a minute.
We want to...
Detach!
Actually.
Soon.
Maybe now.
Hold on.
Uh...
Double check everything.
We need to do...
That...
I think it's fine now, right?
So we detach...
Oh, wait a minute.
Close this.
And now...
Oh my god.
That's fucking awesome.
Look at the dance.
The dance of the craft.
Duna!
Moho!
Eve!
It's almost like this is the orbital plane of the solar system!
That's amazing.
That's actually so cool.
I like that they're a little more bright than the rest of the stars, which should be also quite realistic.
Just like our planets in our solar system.
Joule!
It also fits that it's along the, um...
What do you call it?
The plane of the...
Galaxy.
You know?
Everything's made out of one...
Big collection of...
Dust and gas.
Uh...
We need to start pointing this...
Oh, wait wait wait!
Now we do this!
Wheel authority.
Oh my god, so much better.
Now the question is, are we gonna...
survive?
I think we are.
We have the heat shield.
We can jettison the heat shield!
Why would I do that?
Oh, here we go!
Hold on to your hats!
Ladies and gentlemen.
Oh my goodness.
Whoa!
1700 meters per second right now.
The cool thing is, I don't even need to steer anymore, because it's sort of...
Like the aerodynamic forces are...
What the fuck is that?
Oh, is that my light?
That's my whole stage!
Yo, that's fucking sick!
Look, of course we will be on the same trajectory, obviously.
That's dope!
Yo.
Oh man.
That's cool.
Okay, we gotta...
Uh...
I guess we can do it now.
Oh!
Actually, can I not do this now?
It's not red.
I mean, we're slowing down, so I think we're fine.
Oh my god, it's so beautiful.
Look at that.
Kinda wanna do an EVA right now.
But I have a feeling it's gonna be a bad idea.
I mean...
140 meters per second.
There's gonna be a strong wind.
I don't know if, uh...
He can hold on to the...
To the capsule like that, you know?
Okay.
How come these have not...
Oh.
God dammit.
It happens right when I see it.
So they deployed at 2500 as expected.
This one's gonna deploy at 1000.
Oh my god, it's so pretty.
Imagine just sitting upside down like this.
Coming back down to Earth.
Or Kerbin.
Nice wobble.
And there's the main chute.
Wow!
I thought the main chute was kinda small.
But now compared to these...
It feels, uh...
A lot bigger now.
I can't go faster than this.
What is that?
No alarms.
Detailed stage information.
Whoa!
Here we are!
We made it!
Incredible mission.
Let's go sample the water.
Shall we?
I'm kinda...
I wonder what happens if I let go.
Like, can he swim?
I'm not gonna chance it.
Uh...
EVA report from Kerbin's water.
Okay, so that's not gonna give me anything.
That's too bad.
Huh!
Wait, was that the weight of him?
Making that tip over like that?
I think we're fine.
I don't...
I guess he's in a space suit.
He's gonna float, right?
Like, there's air in his helmet.
He's not...
He's not gonna drown.
32 signs earned.
Oh my god.
So we got crew report from Kerbin's upper atmosphere.
The mystery goo was...
Uh, a sphere.
Temperature scan.
Atmospheric pressure scan.
Beautiful.
And we recovered pretty much everything.
Yo, I wonder...
If it's possible to...
Recover the...
The first stage.
Just like SpaceX, you know?
I know it is possible, but I don't know if people did it with mods.
I know that people have done this in Kerbal Space Program before because I've heard it.
I'm just trying to understand how you even do that.
Because as soon as you let go of that stage, you can't control it anymore.
So...
Hmm.
Yeah, I don't know.
There's probably a way to do it.
No experience gain for that?
What do you mean?
That was like the best mission of all time.
Oh, it's night now.
Huh.
Cute.
Uh-oh.
Oh no.
I see rendering errors.
Why are these clouds lit when there's mountains in front?
Just kidding.
Um...
Uh...
Mission control.
Oh yeah, we did the mission too!
So, we have zero contracts now.
Amazing.
Guys, I think it's time to orbit Kerban.
Wait, ferry three tourists safe to their destination and back?
What?
I mean, hold on.
The space program has just started.
Maybe we should not accept, you know, rich people with money just yet.
Maybe we do some more research and figure out how to even do this.
Do we have the right stuff or not?
This seems a little excessive, doesn't it?
Uh...
Test LV T45 Swivel liquid fuel engine on an escape trajectory out of Kerban.
I mean, we could do that, I guess.
All you would need to do is just go fast.
The question is how fast.
I don't know how much, uh, Kerban weighs, you know?
Or what the mass of Kerban is, I should say, to be more precise.
Hmm...
There's probably info about that somewhere.
That's a pretty easy calculation, too.
I think we should go for this one, though.
No, let's do this one.
And then orbit Kerban afterwards.
Uh...
We've been reviewing our product catalog at Jebediah Kerman's Junkyard and Spacecraft Parts Company...
...and have found an oversight!
There is very little knowledge about how the Swivel liquid fuel engine performs...
...under conditions not found in a...
Okay, so wait, these are all, like, the same description.
These are randomly generated.
There's no way a human...
I mean, a human wrote this, but you know what I mean?
There's just a lot of these variations, I guess.
To perform the test, activate the part through the staging sequence when all test conditions are met.
So that we ha- we have this one.
Uh...
We are at Kerban, I guess?
And on an escape trajectory, okay.
And we get eight science for it if we do it.
Prestige is significant.
Hmm.
Okay.
I think we can do that.
Um...
That seems easy enough, honestly.
But wait a minute.
Do I want to be on an escape trajectory?
I guess it's fine.
We can just burn opposite and come home.
No problem.
Wait, what was I doing just now?
I forgot.
Oh yeah, we were doing the...
...mission here.
So we gotta test...
...the swivel.
I see.
Why do they- Okay, I guess I shouldn't ask questions why they want that tested there.
Let me also save this, uh, important science.
Let's call the next one, uh...
Goodbye.
Because we are leaving the planet.
We are escaping its gravitational hold on us.
We are leaving.
And we will never come back.
Maybe we will.
So this rocket right here is gonna be a masterpiece.
I guess we...
Actually, we can...
We can reuse this part.
Um...
Do we want to keep this part though?
I guess...
I do.
Because you want to do these experiments in different spots, right?
So yeah, all of this is the same.
Um...
The only difference...
Wait, isn't the only difference that we simply...
Uh...
Wait, why does it look like that?
Oh, because...
Ah, this one is here.
We want to change this...
To be that.
Right?
And there we go.
That should...
Otherwise, it's the same.
So wait a minute.
We need to...
Test the swivel liquid fuel engine...
On an escape trajectory.
Okay.
So...
I guess the best way to do that is to just go...
Straight up.
If you go straight up...
Actually, that's not the best.
It may not be the best.
I'm trying to think of energy right now.
So if you're going...
Uh...
We could also add more stages, I guess.
To get more power.
Again, but it is a...
There's a sweet spot there.
Let's just see.
Let's just see if we can do this.
This one, that one...
Oh, I guess I want to combine these.
Ah, wait a minute though.
Oh, wait a minute.
I think I need to activate this...
When I am on this.
And I'm not going to be on that.
Unless I use this.
Wait, is that right?
So I guess...
Yeah, we need another stage.
Wait, I'm actually not sure...
With the formulation here.
What that means.
We're going to have to try.
I think this is fine.
Let's go.
Oh, wait, wait, wait.
Yeah.
Let's see.
Okay, so...
Goodbye.
Are you ready, Jebediah?
We're going to say goodbye to Kerbin now.
Last time, I did bend the path slightly, right?
This time, I'm not going to do that.
We're going to go straight up.
And...
Honestly, I don't know.
It may not be the most efficient thing to do with a rocket.
To go straight up, actually.
If you want to escape.
I'm not entirely sure.
I think it may be something that is unintuitive.
Let's just...
Go.
Maximum speed is there.
We're ready for separation.
Man, it's so pretty.
At night.
Look at that.
Minmus!
Looks like a star in the sky.
Wait, where am I?
Can I not see how high this is?
Okay.
Wait, I need to...
There we go.
Just keeps...
I mean, we're going to revert, I guess, if shit goes south.
We'll see how it goes.
Oh, god.
Keep it straight and narrow.
I need to...
Oh, I need to do something.
Wait, that changed almost nothing.
Precision...
Oh, right.
I need to use precision controls.
There we go.
Oh, no.
This may not be enough.
Kerbin will not let us go!
So, I guess 1,800 meters per second is not enough.
I wish I could see Kerbin's mass.
Then we can calculate it quick.
So, I guess I just...
Can I just...
Space center?
Wait, so I just go this?
Actually, I kind of want to save that.
Okay, here we go.
But I don't...
Actually, I don't want to do this.
I want to go back to...
Vehicle assembly.
We got to change it in here.
Oh wait, so wait.
How do we do this?
I guess we want to add...
Hmm.
I mean, okay.
We could do something naive.
And just see.
We add more.
We just add more.
And...
I am going to add two more.
I don't even know if this is a good idea.
This seems kind of crazy.
Honestly, that looks like a rocket to me, man.
That actually looks kind of sick.
Right?
Oh, wait a minute.
Am I clipping one of these fins?
I am.
Damn.
Good enough.
Or...
No, it's fine.
That's cool.
We're going to go with three.
Actually, maybe put them a little higher.
Just to align them.
So it looks nice.
Oh, yeah!
Look at that.
Okay, so what we want to do is this one and these.
At the same time.
And then we throw all of this away in the ocean.
The thing is though, we're adding a lot of mass now too.
So I don't know if we're actually going to get any higher.
We may have to stage this.
I'm also going to do that.
Let's see.
Craft is too heavy?
The launch pad can't support vessels heavier than 18 tons.
Okay.
Of a goodbye total mass?
Huh?
Oh!
Can't support vessels heavier than 18 tons.
Of a goodbye total mass.
I see.
I guess I'm unable to launch.
Uh...
What is my weight?
Oh.
Oh, we are way above budget.
What the fuck?
Wait, I...
I can't fit more.
Design checklist.
Can I expand this?
Okay.
Electric charge required, but not generated.
These parts consume electric charge, but the vessel is lacking parts that generate it.
Except alternators on engines, but these will only generate charge as long as the alternators are active.
I'm guessing there's no alternator on a solid fuel booster.
It's gotta be the liquid ones.
Cannot transmit science.
Your manned vessel does not have an antenna capable of transmitting science experiment data.
Huh.
I mean...
I know that.
We don't need it right now.
Unused monopropellant resource.
Monopropellant container which is not used by or connecting to anything that requires monopropellant.
I don't know what monopropellant is.
I'm assuming...
It's like a...
I don't know...
Micro adjustments, maybe?
Monopropellant?
Is it for the...
It's probably reaction control stuff.
Should these go off?
Wait, why am I even...
I don't need this part here.
What am I doing?
This is just mass I don't need right now.
Take this off.
Get rid of that.
There we go.
Now we saved some mass.
How much do we have now?
Okay, that's the...
Okay, that was not a lot.
I guess...
The real massive thing here is the fuel, right?
Um...
You know what?
Let's do this.
Let's just keep adding tanks to this and see if we can go higher with this.
How much are we at now?
Okay, we can totally just keep going with this.
Okay, we're approaching 18 tons, but...
We also weigh more, so we're not gonna get as much, uh...
You know, uh, thrust with the engine on this stage.
So that's the trade-off.
We're just gonna make this fit.
Like that.
I mean, we can test, I guess.
There's...
There's also Delta V showing here.
But...
I'm not sure how to read that, because we're gonna go through atmosphere and stuff, and...
That's gonna, I mean...
This depends on where you are, doesn't it?
Like, are you in space or not?
Actually, hold on.
What if we just do another stage in between?
What is this one?
This is the swivel.
Let's put that on the end here.
And then the reliant on the one before that.
Coupling.
Then we go...
There.
This one already has.
Oh my god, this rocket is just going higher and higher.
And we're not above, uh, mass limit now.
Let's see, so this one...
Oh, we have an issue!
This one first.
Then...
Oh wait, how do I...
This one, that one...
Gone.
Then we have the engine.
It burns.
And then...
Cut.
Gone.
This burns.
Cut off.
And then we have the parachutes.
Oh.
Uh, yeah, that's fine.
This one, that one...
Alright, let's go!
Goodbye.
Launching at night.
Well, late evening.
Um...
Full speed.
Is that...
And we wanna...
Wait, what?
Valentina!
Why are you in here?
Oh!
Look at that!
Whoops!
How do I actually...
Show me the top!
Oh my god, the camera is so weird.
Oh, it's like a cut out.
A cut off thing.
No, the camera is so weird.
Okay, whatever.
Oh, that's the...
Orientation!
They're...
Ah!
That makes sense.
And that's the window right there.
Oh, that's cool.
Okay!
Oh yeah!
We're heavy now!
Come on!
Oi!
Let's get out of this gravity fuel!
Holy crap!
But we're gonna have more fuel...
Uh, for the liquid fuel stage.
And we're gonna be higher up in the atmosphere, where there's...
Uh, less...
Well, atmosphere.
Less air resistance to fight against.
I'm trying to keep it sort of straight, but it's not wanting to do that.
Is that because I have this?
No.
Wheel authority is at 100%.
Oh my god, it's like tilting to one side!
Here we go, here we go, here we go, here we go!
Keep going straight up.
Oh wait, do I have precision controls turned on?
Uh...
No I don't.
I don't think so.
Whew!
Oh yeah.
That's nice.
But then we have another stage!
Um...
Can I actually change this mid-flight?
I can.
You ready?
What?
Oh okay, okay.
I don't know what just happened...
Whoa!
That's sensitive.
Wait...
What?
Huh?
Uh...
What is that?
Can we escape?
Wait, did I not reset this guy?
Is that why Valentina is here?
I can't click on it.
Wait a minute.
What?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
I'm confused.
Wait a sec.
What?
Wait, can we actually...
It's moving!
In any case, we're not on any escape trajectory here.
It's still not enough.
The thing is though, if you burn a lot of...
Oh man, I'm kind of confused about this.
Wait a sec.
I need to...
Space center.
Wait, what did I do?
How did this happen?
Ongoing missions.
Oh my god.
Okay.
Jebediah!
Oh shit!
Okay, so hold on.
We gotta...
Make sure this guy comes home.
And I guess we don't have any fuel left here.
Which is fine.
We're gonna fall back to...
Kerbin.
That's so pretty, man.
I love when that happens.
Look at that.
So nice.
Oh, it's the moon!
Right in the center.
Of my view.
Very cool.
Okay, so we need to...
Get ready for entry here.
I guess we would have to point towards...
Planets.
Wait, are we still...
Oh, we're still rising!
360,000...
Meters.
Holy shit.
It's only now that we're...
Turning around here and moving back, but...
Man.
We are gonna be hauling ass.
Not to mention...
Valentina.
Oh, you can speed up.
A lot.
10x.
50x.
Oh!
Point down.
Precision.
Dude, I...
I think next time I play this...
I'm gonna try and connect a controller.
Or like a joystick.
I mean...
Because I kind of want to try and control it with that, you know?
It's like my first instinct.
That would be cool.
Oh, wait!
We're gonna be dropping down...
In the darkness.
Hmm.
This guy is just...
Always happy...
To be doing whatever it is we're doing.
So we're at 180...
Uh...
Thousand meters right now.
When does the atmosphere sort of start?
Let's actually try and pay attention.
I'm gonna go a little faster.
But it feels like it would be...
Right above...
Now...
Ish.
No?
Oh!
I think when the music stops...
Shit's about to get real, you know?
It's not completely dark.
Holy shit!
I mean...
Heat shield...
We're fine, right?
Woah!
What's happening?
What's that sound?
It sounds like something just...
Exploded!
I think we're good.
Oh, that's so pretty!
Parachute!
And this one was...
250 and below.
Meters per second.
Speed up.
Oh my god, where are we right now?
Is this Finland?
What are all these lakes?
Thousand lakes.
They actually call it the country with a thousand lakes.
Main chute has deployed.
Oh my god.
I'm guessing that was one of my earlier stages from this one.
Eh, that's probably what it was.
For a second I was like, is that my other...
Up there?
Up there, but there's no way.
Definitely not yet.
Speed down.
We're at 50 meters now.
Ah!
Okay!
Okay, we're fine.
Hey, we're on the beach!
Look at that!
That's nice.
Made it home.
Dude, this game is so much fun.
I love that.
Yeah, we got all that back.
Jebediah is safe.
Um...
Tracking station.
What are these, like, lions?
Also, why does it look like that?
Fly.
700 kilometers!
Yo, I mean...
Tell me that isn't a beautiful view.
Damn.
This game has come a long way.
I'm gonna try and find, like, a screenshot after this of...
Of what it looked like back when I played this the first time.
It was nothing...
Like this.
Nothing.
And this is all mods, by the way.
Graphical mods.
We're on our way down.
I am afraid, though.
Because we are gonna come in...
Pretty hot.
Let me have a look here.
Nothing.
Can I control this wall?
Oh, yeah, I can!
Whee!
Let me do a rotation this way.
Whoa!
That's the sun.
Oh!
Oh, is that the Earth?
I mean, carbon?
Oh!
Look at that!
That's sick.
Oh, my God!
Valentina is so excited!
Look at her!
She is just in awe.
She has the overview effect right now.
Which is apparently something that astronauts get.
It's what they call it, you know?
You get this view of the entire Earth all at once.
And apparently, your perception of everything on Earth changes after that.
Like, everyone who experiences that are never the same afterwards, you know?
I wonder what that would feel like.
Oh,
man.
This looks so scary.
But it's safe!
We're at 300 kilometers!
It doesn't feel safe, though, when you look at the planet coming into view like that.
In fact, we should probably detach here.
Bye-bye!
That's gonna crash into the planet a little further away from me.
But approximately the same place.
Gotta find...
This way...
Okay, I'm getting used to the opposite controls here.
Dude, we're already moving at 2,000!
Oh, it's gonna get worse.
Let's see if the heat shield can...
I'm pretty sure I would have died here if not for the heat shield.
Because remember that little bar that came the other time?
It was like at 90%.
It got so hot.
So we should be...
Let me actually see exactly when this happens.
When does the effect...
Oh, is that lightning?
Saw something down there.
Something just flashed.
65,000 meters.
65 kilometers.
Holy shit, man.
Wait, we're not even slowing down!
We are.
Oh yeah, we're slowing down now.
We just had to get to the dense atmosphere.
I can't... What if there's a...
I clicked wrong!
Okay, it worked!
I was like, what if there's a mountain?
I can't see shit!
Oh, man.
I need fucking radar...
Sensors to measure the distance to the ground.
Fuck me!
I can't see nothing.
Oh my god.
This must be so scary.
I see the moon.
Never mind.
Moon is gone.
I guess we're in a cloud.
Oh!
I mean, supposedly we're 3,000 meters above the surface.
And the drogue chutes haven't even deployed yet.
Why do they always deploy right when I see it?
Fucking hell, it's like they can hear me.
Making me look weird here.
Okay, so at 1,000, the main chute should deploy.
But the thing is, what if there's a mountain in the way?
Dress.
Speed up.
Oh, that's water!
That's water!
We're safe.
I see water.
Oh my god.
I need night vision.
I gotta find some carrots.
Yep, did you hear that?
That was my other stage.
Smashing into the ocean.
I wish there's a way to remove the UI.
I kinda just wanna see.
Oh, I can't check key bindings now.
For next time, I'm gonna prepare like a cheat sheet for myself with like key bindings.
On the second monitor, you know?
60 meters 50.
Gonna slow down to really see this.
Splash down!
Welcome home!
Yeah, you're gonna be here for a couple weeks.
I hope you brought snacks.
Did we even- Wait, why did I do this?
I forgot.
Oh yeah, we wanted to escape, uh...
Kerbin.
We didn't get any signs out of it.
Hey, but Valentina got experience.
What does that actually mean?
Where's the, uh...
That one?
Wait a minute.
Effects...
Oh!
Flighted Kerbin 1.
Oh, that's cool!
They get stats!
They get to say, Oh, I've orbited the planet 78 times or something like that or something.
That's cool.
Effect Stability Assist.
Full Vessel Control without ComNet Access.
How do I- What- Oh, wait, what?
Oh!
Uh, I mean...
I guess this is fine.
You know what we can do?
We can give them separate suits depending on their job.
Bob, so this guy is an engineer.
Let's give him, like, this color.
Wait, what?
Oh, with helmet.
Okay, I see.
We even get to choose a color?
That's funny.
No, I like that.
Yeah, that's good.
So this is a scientist.
Bob.
You are gonna be blue.
Why are you blue?
Wonderful.
Okay.
Um...
Maybe there's, like, applicant- Okay, applicants.
Wait, there's a stupidity setting?
Courage and stupidity.
For what?
Why would I ever take someone who's stupid?
That's, like, the last thing you want for people in a space program.
But I love it, though.
That's funny.
Uh...
I thought there would be, like, a little tech tree for these pilots here.
But I can't seem to find it.
But it has, like...
There's, like, levels, right?
And they have, uh, effects.
So...
I don't know.
It's a bit weird.
Yeah.
Also, uh...
Can I just...
Oh my god, look at that.
Phew.
I'm gonna wait till...
It's daylight.
Oh!
Okay, we had a bit of a shower there.
Oy!
Perfect day to do some rocketry, wouldn't you say?
We have 48 science!
Ooh, let's see what we can unlock now.
Advanced rocketry.
All kinds of engines here.
Star shot?
What even is that?
Uh,
what is...
I don't know what that is.
Wait, hold on.
What is this?
Jebediah Kerman eats danger for breakfast.
Lunch and dinner.
At his day job as the KSC resident daredevil pilot.
But what does he do when he wants to relax on the weekends?
He fills firework canisters at his state-of-the-art junkyard facility.
The star shot 8 has enough fireworks for a quick show.
Or you can set up an array of them to really rival the big bangs on the launch pad.
Guaranteed to go off when you want them to or the next one is half off.
So, fireworks?
If you think about it...
Space program is just...
Fireworks with humans inside them.
Uh, I guess I kinda wanna try that.
But I do wanna unlock something.
Maybe something in here.
Mark 1 crew cabin.
I guess this is just a bigger one.
25?
CD18.
RF... P1 flag?
A flag that can be applied to size 1 tanks and other parts with the same curvature.
To show PRIDE in your mission.
Or use a different flag if you really wanna go that way.
No, I would always use this flag that I have here, because it's beautiful.
Flight control.
Winglets.
Small inline reaction wheel.
But I mean...
Uh...
The parts themselves must have reaction wheels.
Otherwise, how am I able to control them?
Like, without engines, I'm able to steer them.
There's gotta be reaction wheels in there.
Maybe this just gives me more.
Basic science.
ProBoto...
Bodine...
Stay Putnik!
That's a great name!
Rechargeable battery pack.
Science Junior.
Okay, so this is all, like, science stuff.
Most of it.
A large radiator panel.
Okay.
High gain antenna.
Oh!
I get it!
I understand why you would want these antennas now.
So, okay.
Let's say you don't have enough fuel to come home.
At least you can send the data...
And...
You know...
Without coming home.
And...
There you go.
That's it.
That's why.
Like, if you don't plan on coming home.
Or...
If you get, like, a rover, right?
You want the antenna to send data back, of course.
Because you can get rovers in this game.
That's why you would use that.
Uh...
I'm kind of intrigued by this stuff.
Or this.
But this is just...
More...
Engines.
Wait, this one seems really bad.
14...
Wait, that's nothing.
60 kilonewtons in vacuum.
Wasn't the other one, like, 200?
Yeah.
Weighs half a ton.
Okay, it weighs a lot less, I guess.
There's gotta be more to this.
Oh, wait a minute.
Maybe the efficiency...
What did this one say?
345.
Gimbal.
Engine stops under 10%?
Maybe the fuel pressure is just not gonna be enough?
Or something?
Oh!
Wait a minute!
This has to mean at sea level, right?
So...
It has more thrust.
I don't...
I forget what ISP stands for, but it's definitely like...
Um...
I think it's like an efficiency thing.
This one has more at sea level.
310 vacuum.
345, right?
Terrible!
When you're on the ground.
It's basically like...
So, you know how...
So, think about this.
You know, there's like solar sails.
I don't know if there's solar sails in this game, but the concept is there, right?
Photons hitting it and, you know, giving it thrust.
You wouldn't use that to get off the ground on Earth.
You wouldn't be able to have enough thrust, right?
But!
In space, you can get very far with it.
It's just very slow.
So, it's like that.
Man, I don't know what to pick!
And I can only pick one!
Fuck!
I...
Okay, this one I don't care about, I think.
I'm like, torn between this one?
Because look at this.
Science.
Experiment...
I mean...
I feel like we gotta take this.
This seems like the most fun, doesn't it?
This doesn't even seem that crazy.
Whoa!
Okay, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Hold on a minute.
Whoa!
Whew!
Okay.
Maybe we want this, just so we can get this.
Look at all this crap!
Dang.
The next logical step for rocketry technology is just to go bigger.
Yes.
But then again...
If this is gonna give us more science...
Right?
Then maybe this is worth it.
Maybe we need to do this in order to do that.
I also don't know if we actually can end up getting all of it, or if it's like a thing where you have to choose.
You know, if I take something over here, will I then forever be locked out of this?
Stuff like that.
So I have to consider that too.
I think in any case...
You know, putting points into research early...
Could be good, because that would essentially speed up research later.
I think that idea is quite common in games.
I'm gonna do that.
I still have over 200,000, so that's good.
We can do some experiments now.
Archives.
Oh!
It's all our science!
Oh, that's cool.
Review science report.
Situations.
Surface landed, surface...
Oh!
Flying low, flying high, in space low.
Ah, yeah, okay, okay.
So this is a way to keep track of that.
So I guess I wanna go in space high next.
And...
Obviously, there's gonna be...
Whoops, I just launched my mouse across the desk.
There's also gotta be, like, different situations on different planets.
Obviously, right?
If I go to the moon, I would wanna, you know, do a crew report there, for example.
Also, why can't I see that here?
Oh, I guess I can.
Yeah, so we don't have any here.
We only have on Kerbin.
Right!
Okay.
Experiments, crew report...
Oh, that's nice.
That's actually so nice that they keep track of this.
This is gonna help a lot.
Um...
Dude, we are...
We're gonna go orbit.
It's time to orbit!
We have a mission.
Orbit Kerbin.
Yes.
We need to achieve a stable orbit around Kerbin.
All you should need to do is throw yourself at the ground and miss.
Beautifully put.
Because that's exactly what it is.
Falling with style.
In...
Perpetuity.
Assuming no air resistance.
Haha.
Accept!
Also, what's the other one I have?
Oh yeah, I never did this!
Because I never could get on an escape trajectory.
Honestly, I think it may be harder...
To go...
To go on an escape trajectory than it is to attain orbit.
Because, uh...
It seems like Kerbin be...
Thick, you know?
Kerbin be a...
Chonky boy.
Lots of mass there.
Okay, let's make it!
Let's do it!
Um...
Oh, where's my last one?
Can I not...
Open?
We can start with this one.
And work our way from there.
Actually, no, no, no.
Start from the importance.
Um...
Let's call this ship...
Falling...
No, let's just call it...
Perpetuity.
I like that.
We go round...
And round...
Forever.
I like that!
Save it.
Actually, we need to save it later, but...
It's good to save it now, I guess.
Okay, I guess I wanna keep this anyway.
We wanna do science.
And...
Uh...
Let me think.
So...
To go to orbit...
We basically just wanna...
We wanna...
We wanna get up high.
And then just...
Burn, uh...
Tangentially to the planet.
In the direction we're going.
And if we...
If we burn...
Hmm, let me think.
Yeah, we just wanna burn...
Yeah, horizontally, I guess.
We just wanna...
Go fast, so we miss...
The curvature.
That's all it is.
And the cool thing about this game is that...
You have to sort of...
Like, in real life, you would calculate all this, right?
And have a computer program, make sure that you do all the right things at the right times.
But this is a video game, right?
So you get to just control it.
We're just gonna be sick.
Um...
This may actually already...
Be enough.
No.
We need to...
This was the old one.
We gotta add more.
Oh, wait.
Take this one.
Did I take the wrong one?
God damn it.
Remove that shroud.
Let's add some more...
Fuel to this.
Just one more.
The idea now is...
This is gonna take us up through the thick part of the atmosphere.
The very dense part.
And as soon as we're up there with less air assistance, we're gonna use this and hopefully achieve enough speed...
To go around the planet.
And...
Of course...
Save some for the home trip.
So we have this one.
This is...
Oh man.
Wish I could just see.
Okay.
Sanity check complete.
Then after that...
We're...
I...
Hmm.
No, wait.
I guess we're gonna do this first.
And then we do this.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hold on.
No.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
I misread.
This is correct.
Because this one burns after this one.
We burn that.
And then that's the last one we do.
And then the parachutes.
Yeah.
This is it.
I like it.
Oh, wait a minute.
Did we also unlock some new stuff?
Or did I not choose anything?
Maybe I chose not to choose anything.
Oh no, I did.
Battery packs.
Hmm.
High gain antenna.
Science Junior.
Oh, it's big.
Whoa.
I don't...
I don't know if I should.
It's just more mass.
We're just gonna go orbit.
What is it?
Yeah.
Okay.
Let's see if this is enough.
We can come back and change it.
We can do some trial and error here.
Oh, beautiful.
Look at that.
What time is it?
Four in the morning.
Perfect time to launch, I guess.
I wonder if there's actually, like, wind.
Wind.
I mean, I see the clouds moving, but...
Could just be, you know...
Like, I don't know if there's real wind affecting my...
Ooh.
Maybe not the best time to launch.
But fuck it.
We're going.
Uh, speed.
Houston, we have liftoff.
Perpetuity in search of falling.
Again and again.
That's the mission.
Oh my god.
There's actually lightning back there.
Haha.
Sweet.
We can start turning.
Wait a minute.
The question is now, we have to turn with the planet though.
Uh...
I don't know which way the planet is spinning.
Because we wanna not work against that.
I didn't think about this.
Shit.
Hold on.
Revert flight.
Back.
I need to see something.
Save.
And I guess I just...
Go here.
Wait, I actually...
I need to see where we are.
Can I speed up time?
It's...
It's going that way.
So it's going what I...
What I call east.
But it's apparently not east.
According to the bowl.
And...
And that was...
It's like this shape.
It's like towards the point.
Basically what I'm trying to figure out here...
So in real life when you launch rockets...
You wanna be launching...
Um...
With the rotation of the earth.
It's like being...
It's like...
The earth already has a lot of rotation.
Right?
That's why you always run...
Launch close to the equator.
Because the speed there is...
Is the max.
Right?
On a planet.
If you launch at the pole...
You don't get any extra push.
Or like pull.
At the start.
So that's why I'm checking that.
Uh...
So that means...
Now...
Yeah.
That way.
Dude, I'm just gonna call this east.
And you know what?
Assuming...
Like...
Just like real life.
The planet is spinning...
East, you know?
That's why the sun is rising in the east.
Wait, is the sun rising?
It should be rising in the east.
Because it's spinning east.
Why does this say north though?
Am I losing my...
Maybe it's not saying north.
Is that a number?
I don't...
I don't know.
That's weird.
We're gonna go that way.
There's probably like an orb...
Like a um...
What do you call it?
Proper and...
Mathematically optimized...
Path you wanna take here?
But I don't know when to start turning, you know?
Obviously you don't just wanna go up and then right.
So you wanna do something in between.
I'm gonna start turning now.
Slightly.
Wait, I can't.
I have like no control.
Why can't I control?
Ah!
Oh shit.
Oh, here we go.
Here we go.
Slightly right.
Oh wait, we're going really fast here.
This may not be a good idea.
I don't think you wanna have these atmospheric...
Effects on the way up.
That's too fast.
Can I...
How far?
Oh, Jesus!
Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop.
Oh, okay.
I guess we stop.
Uh...
We don't have enough.
For this.
We need more fuel.
Then again, I could've just burned more...
This way.
Maybe that would've been enough, actually.
If I had done this better.
Let me try it one more time.
Uh, launch.
We're gonna start turn...
No, no, no, no.
Actually, uh...
Go back to...
Assembly.
I'm gonna modify this slightly.
Let's do...
How much are we weighing?
Okay.
Um...
Let's add one more tank.
Make it orange.
And then I think I'm gonna combine these...
No, no, wait.
That's wrong.
These two.
So that they start immediately when I click.
Okay, here we go.
Max speed.
We're gonna turn a lot earlier this time.
Maybe like, uh...
3,000 or something.
I have a little bit of control right now, but it's not a lot.
I guess...
I guess it must be the reaction wheels in the pod working against all this mass.
So it's kinda...
It makes sense, you know?
Like, I can't turn.
I'm turning as hard as I can.
And...
Boom.
See, now I can turn, because the mass is much lower.
Okay, we're gonna turn way more steeply here.
Let's go like, almost horizontally here.
Let me see.
I wish I could see how high it goes.
Uh... Oh wait, my shit is...
Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop.
Okay, we have some fuel left.
We go up top and we burn tangentially.
Why do we go top?
Because there's no air resistance.
Um, let me...
Speed up a bit.
I guess you...
You can't burn all of it instantaneously, so you have to sort of...
I guess go a little before.
Let's say that's fine.
Tangential to planet.
Like that.
Actually, right on the horizon line.
Oh wait, we're facing the wrong way.
Whoops.
Don't wanna do that.
Yeah, there we go.
Max speed!
Yeah.
Look at that.
But we don't have any fuel left soon.
We may not make it.
Shit!
It was close!
Look at that!
Still suborbital.
Honestly, not too bad.
We're close.
Um...
We can just revert immediately.
Okay, I understand why you guys wanted me to play on moderate.
If we couldn't do that...
Mmm...
That would've been kinda crazy.
That's for a second playthrough, right?
Okay, so...
Basically...
What I'm seeing here...
Is that we just...
Let's make another stage, actually.
Let's do this.
One more here.
I'm even gonna color it differently.
Let's make these.
Uh, engines...
I don't know why you wouldn't use the Reliant.
It's just better.
And then we need a...
Thingy here.
This goes on.
And then we do another one.
No.
Uh, another engine.
And...
This one.
Oh my god.
I don't even know if this solid rocket booster can lift this thing, though.
This is a lot of mass.
We're almost at AT!
This is crazy!
I actually forgot about the mass restriction, but I guess we're okay here.
Um...
Let's just confirm this.
So we're gonna...
Shroud that.
Shroud...
Or, unshroud it.
Let's see here, so...
Oh, this is wrong already.
It's wrong.
Move this all the way down here.
So this one first...
And...
Oh my god, it's all...
It's all whack.
Why did...
Why is it like this?
Oh, wait a minute!
We have...
We have two of these.
Okay.
So this one...
First.
Uh, wrong.
It's this one.
Goes off, and after that...
This engine, and then this goes up here.
In fact, we can even do this.
So that this goes off, and this turns on immediately.
I'm actually gonna put this here.
That one, and then...
These are always gonna be the same.
These three.
And put the shroud back on.
I'm not sure this booster can actually get the job done.
Let's see, shall we?
It's gonna be slow if it does.
I guess I could've checked the...
Thrust to weight ratio.
Max speed.
And...
Are you ready, Jebediah?
Ooh!
More slow!
But I guess that's kinda realistic too.
Think of the space shuttle, right?
Right at launch, it's kinda slow.
It needs to build up.
As time goes on, mass decreases, you know.
You get more thrust.
To weight ratio.
You're gonna go faster.
Oh, I'm starting to lean left here for some reason.
We don't want that.
Start leaning right.
Uh...
Something is making it go left.
You're going the wrong way!
Captain!
Jebediah!
The other way.
Okay.
I guess we're gonna have to wait for the liquid fuel.
There we go.
Let's start slightly turning here.
This looks so cool!
Come on.
Okay, he's definitely having issues...
I think wind resistance is playing a factor here.
And of course, we have more mass compared to last time.
I'm pushing hard right as I can, you know.
Like, it doesn't want to budge.
That's all she wrote!
Uh, let's see.
Okay.
We may need more juice here.
Get rid of that crap.
Well, that's nice.
Like, it's kinda...
You can see that it's been hot.
That's a neat detail.
Off we go.
I'm gonna already start sort of pointing a little horizontal here.
Whoa!
Uh, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop.
Let's wait until we're a little higher.
Then we're gonna go completely tangential.
Like that, right on the line.
Ah, we may not have enough here.
Then again, it's more than last time.
Speed it up.
Losing speed, of course.
Ideally, you want to burn when you're moving fast.
Because if you look at the energy involved, kinetic energy goes as speed squared, right?
So any difference there is gonna matter a lot more if you start out fast.
But, uh, obviously you can't do that here, because you're gonna be slower up here.
But you don't want to be burning down there, because there's atmosphere.
Okay, let's try!
We're gonna start now.
No?
Oh no!
Shitballs!
Ah!
It felt like we had more fuel there, compared to last time.
But I guess, last time we had three tanks, now we have two.
Dang, dude!
How far up are we?
Hundred...
Okay, honestly, man, we don't need to go this high.
You know, we could definitely settle in a lower orbit.
I think that's my mistake here.
And most of it is because I can't control the rocket initially.
The solid rocket booster is making it difficult.
Hmm.
Um...
Okay, so what should...
Oh!
What the fuck am I doing with this?!
Get the hell out of here!
I forgot about that!
Okay, we saved some mass.
God damn!
Uh, anything else?
That I forgot.
I don't know.
Uh...
Dude, I kinda wanna put more boosters.
Is that crazy?
Check it out.
What if...
Hmm...
I may have an idea.
What if we don't use any...
Solid rocket boosters at all?
Okay?
So we're gonna say goodbye to you.
Let's try to do full liquid.
Just to feel the difference.
So, I like this here.
I actually like this too.
Nah, maybe it's...
Too much.
Do we do...
Maybe only two...
Maybe two stages.
Let's say we just add a bunch more of these.
Because now we don't have the solid rocket booster.
We have so much, uh...
Extra mass we can work with.
That also feels like a waste, doesn't it?
Let's turn this orange.
I mean, I kinda like it.
We put on these guys.
Let's put...
Four.
Right?
So now this burns, and then we...
I guess this one is this one, right?
I need to confirm every time.
Yeah, it's that one.
Okay?
And then we have the rocket up here that burns.
And hopefully this will take us to orbit.
Let's try.
And this time, I'm going to...
I'm going to, uh...
Go even more horizontal, like earlier.
We're gonna go...
Whoa, this one is balancing on...
A very tiny point there.
This doesn't look...
Right, does it?
This looks weird.
Okay, well here we go.
Uh, speed.
Jebediah?
Are you ready?
Perpetuity?
This is it.
Let's try and...
Whoa.
Let's try and turn it like...
3000 this time.
Can I actually control much?
It's still very difficult.
I feel like I have more control.
No, I don't.
I wish I could turn...
I can't turn, like...
Maybe it's just too much wind.
Too much air.
Too dense.
But I guess, I mean...
The more air you have, the more these fins...
Should do work, right?
If there's no air, they're useless.
So I feel like it should be more responsive down...
Closer to the ground?
Like, I am turning this way as much as I can.
I'm holding the button.
That's how much I'm trying to turn.
I don't know why the rocket wants to go left so bad.
Turn, you bastard!
Turn!
Ah!
Eee!
Ah...
My god, man.
What the fuck?
Shit.
Okay, we're turning!
But am I already sort of...
On a crazy trajectory?
Oh my god, what the fuck is that?
We're gonna revert.
I gotta figure this out, man.
I need to figure out how to turn!
Maybe it is, uh...
The reaction wheel thing.
I'm in control, though, but...
Oh, maybe I didn't unlock it.
I saw it.
Right, I didn't buy it yet.
Damn!
Hmm...
Huh.
Oh, shit.
Maybe we do need to...
Okay, hold on.
Dude, I love trying to figure this out.
This is fun, man.
Let's see, so I have three...
I have 3.5 sides.
I can't unlock shit.
Nevermind, nevermind.
I thought I could unlock some...
I don't know, better...
Uh, control thingies.
We can maybe try the other one.
It's called Swivel!
The LV-T45 can deflect its thrust to aid in...
Craft control!
That's the trade-off.
That's why you wanna use this sometimes, I guess.
But let's see if it actually works.
I guess...
Gimbal, right?
Uh...
Speed!
Go!
Whoa, it's definitely...
Not as strong, though.
Wow!
Oh, but look at...
Oh, yeah, look at the gimbal action!
Okay, this is how you do it.
I see, so the other one, you get more power, but you have less control.
That's the trade-off.
Maybe turning now is a bit too early, actually.
Let's just calm down a bit.
Let's not make it too crazy here.
I have a fat feeling about this rocket here.
This rocket sucks ass.
Kinda hard to keep aligned.
Whoa.
Man, this is so much slower than the other engine.
That's crazy.
I guess we can slowly sort of start to...
Turn slightly.
I guess the good news is...
Since we're going slower, we're not gonna start, uh...
Building up a bunch of forces up front.
From drag, you know?
Like, the faster you go, the...
More drag you get, right?
I'm not actually sure what the...
Like, is it like a square dependence there?
Or maybe even more?
Definitely more than...
To the power of one, I mean.
I don't know what the fuck I'm talking about.
I'm trying to focus on keeping this rocket stable here.
Keep going right, keep going right.
We're at 15 kilometers now.
We're gonna keep turning.
Oh, we're actually running out of fuel here.
Shit.
Come on.
Okay.
How's it look?
I feel like we need more.
I like that.
I like that, actually.
May not be enough, but let's see.
I'm gonna start pointing this way now.
Oh, it's gonna take a while.
Okay, I think...
As soon as the music starts, I think we're in space.
Meaning, like...
There's no air anymore.
Let's wait a bit more.
Oh, let's go!
Go too fast!
Okay, let's go, let's go.
Focus on this.
Let's see if we...
Oh my god, the fuel goes down so fast!
We don't have enough.
Ah, fuck me.
Dang it.
Ah!
It's so close!
Dude, this game is hard!
How the fuck did I ever land on the moon back then?
I don't understand.
You know what it is?
It's because you probably had access to all the good shit at that time.
Like, there was no campaign, you know?
I probably had the biggest and baddest engines and shit.
That's why.
Boom.
Okay, so...
This is nice for turning, but it sucks for everything else.
So how about a middle ground?
Watch this.
We're gonna get rid of these three.
Put this in there.
We're gonna...
Let me see.
Oh yeah, actually, at sea level, this one is much more powerful.
Look at that.
I thought it was a smaller difference, but yeah.
Yeah, that's fine.
This one there.
And then...
Do I go for the solid booster?
I do like it.
I do like those son of a guns.
But I feel like this is a rocket I've tried before.
Maybe not the exact one, right?
But...
Hmm.
Maybe add one more fuel tank to this.
Uno mas.
And just so it's not completely similar, we're gonna add a little extra fuel tank up here too.
In fact, we're gonna...
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Let's add a tiny, tiny, teeny fuel tank there.
Make it fit with the rest somehow.
There we go.
Now, that's what I'm talking about.
That's a rocket right there.
This one, this one in there, I'm gonna assume it's right.
That one...
Ah shit, I can't assume it's right.
So if that's right, the other one is right.
Good.
And then this one at the end.
Boom, boom, bam.
And we...
Ah, but wait!
We're overweight!
Crap!
Okay, get rid of one of these.
We're still overweight!
Ah, man!
Wait, how...
How am I ever gonna get anywhere if I can't build a big rocket here?
Actually, hold on a minute.
What?
Yeah, something's off about that.
Uh...
Wait a sec.
I need to think about this one.
Maybe you need to...
Wait a sec.
Miniaturization.
No, wait.
I thought that was something else.
Hmm.
Wait a sec.
Rocketry.
Uh...
I need to look at...
Centers?
Instruction...
Facilities.
Oh!
As your career progresses, you will find that you've outgrown your original space center.
Luckily, the Kerbal engineering department has your back.
And through judicious application of funds, you can upgrade each of the facilities from basic to world-class.
So the launch pad, I guess.
Facility damage.
Whether by errant trajectory, decoupler issues, or even nefarious circumstance, you may find that you've damaged one of the facilities.
You can recover from these issues by repairing the facility.
At a cost, of course.
But how?
Oh, right!
I saw a button like this, actually, earlier.
600,000?!
Bro, I'm... broke?
Oh, max parts support...
It's gotta be...
Yeah!
Hey, we can do that now!
75,000 is not even that bad.
And then we can have 140 tons.
Boom!
No problem!
Oh my god, we're going all in now!
You kidding me?
Put this back.
Make it look nice.
Cut me some slack.
There we go.
I think this one will perform.
Uh...
Okay, we're gonna get off the ground, at least.
That's...
Uh...
Wait a minute.
Oh, maybe I should just look at this, actually.
So...
3,500 now.
I wonder if it calculates, like...
Or takes into account...
The thing is, though, like...
Yes, I can just keep adding, right?
Let's say I do this.
Yay!
I have a bunch of Delta V.
But...
Oh, I can still get off the ground.
Okay, but...
I don't know if this engine down here is gonna be good enough to...
Hmm...
You know what I mean?
Let's get rid of these two.
I feel like we're too slow now.
This feels more right.
Why are these out like that?
Weird.
Okay, this seems...
Okay.
Let's try.
Save it.
Save.
Go.
Here we go.
It's just getting...
Oh wait, my fins are here.
Ah, that's probably fine.
Because I can't control it anyways with the solid booster.
It's okay.
Ooh, we're heavy.
Oi, oi, oi.
I mean, the rocket looks cool.
I like the way it looks.
It's already wanting to turn left for some reason.
Maybe there's a strong wind from the east.
Actually, something else.
I shouldn't be looking at...
Where I'm aiming here.
I should be looking at where the vector is going.
Because that's what matters.
Oh, I should have been faster with that.
I fucked up.
Oh my god.
Come on.
Now we need to turn.
Why do you want to go down?
Stop!
Ah, you bastard!
Why you gotta be this...
I can't turn.
Even with this little mass?
Come on.
Oh my god.
I am trying to turn as hard as I can right now.
I can't.
Maybe if I slow down a bit?
Is there an argument to be made for having...
No, there's actually not.
You want to get through the thick atmosphere as fast as possible.
The fuck was that?
Ah, this is already...
We're fucked already.
Like, this is bad.
Bad rocket.
We may need to swivel here.
Yes.
You know what?
I'm just gonna go back immediately.
We need to swivel there.
Because at that point, we're already quite high and it should be okay.
This...
This is the rocket, guys.
This is the one that will do it.
Delete that.
You ready?
This is it.
And...
There.
The final rocket, baby.
Guys, am I gonna...
Am I gonna reach orbit now?
Yes or no?
I am actually gonna go all in and say...
On this trip...
Yes.
You ready?
Here we go.
We're gonna have much more control with the swivel...
As soon as this solid booster is gone.
I'm turning already.
Maybe it's too early.
And the reason you don't want to turn too early is that you expose more surface area to the wind.
Slowing you down.
And now I'm kind of stuck in this...
Vector.
I actually can't...
Go back.
Oh, but look at...
Look at this.
Now we have control.
Feels much better.
But it's also a weak engine.
So, you know.
There's that.
Oh my god.
The rocket's like wobbling.
Look at that.
It's like a...
Dildo, man.
Look at the way it's fucking wobbling.
What the fuck?
This thing is unstable as hell.
It's gonna explode any moment.
Okay, we're gonna...
Oh shit.
Keep...
I'm gonna keep my eye on the ball.
Wait!
Is that where that expression comes from?
You know how people say keep your eye on the ball?
Is to keep the eye on the ball when fucking flying a spacecraft.
A nav ball.
Oh my god.
I organically just said that out loud.
Like...
I'm gonna keep my eye on the ball.
Okay, I'm turning horizontal a little.
We're gonna use up this entire stage for horizontalism.
Or like barely horizontalism.
Let's see.
Oh my god.
We're not even that high.
But I guess it kinda looks like we're out of the atmosphere.
Hard to say.
Just start in any case.
Just keep...
boosting.
Okay, we have a lot more fuel.
Let's start going a little...
Okay, we're going too fast.
Oh, we're gonna slow down though.
All this air resistance.
I think we went too shallow here.
We should've gone up more.
Maybe speed it up a bit.
I don't want to go too high again.
Okay, here we go.
Here we go.
We're gonna go horizontal.
Look at all that fuel we have.
Come on, baby.
Come on, yeah.
Burn it up.
We have...
Okay, okay.
We have a lot of fuel.
Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop.
We made it.
Okay, it's it's very thin atmosphere.
Did we actually make it?
Fly a vessel up and out of the atmosphere and accelerate parallel with the surface until you're in a stable orbit.
Yeah, but...
I...
Yeah, I guess I'm not orbiting cause I'm still in the atmosphere.
Oh shit.
In that case I have to burn opposite.
I have to go here and burn.
In any case, we are not slowing down considerably so we are actually good.
Guys, I think we got it.
We got it.
It's so quiet up here in space.
Let's do a crew report.
Upper atmosphere, nothing new, huh?
Okay.
Look at our speed.
2500 meters per second.
That is so fast.
So we are going to move up here and slow down.
But it's not going to be by a lot, I think.
Maybe we are going to reach 2000 or something.
I don't know.
I wonder if we reach there, if the thing is going to activate.
Or maybe it needs to be an orbit above a certain height all around.
Because if this hits atmosphere every time, this orbit is going to decay over time.
Every time I pass through here, this is going to decrease until I, you know, burn up in the atmosphere.
So right now, if we do nothing, Jebediah is actually doomed.
He is a dead man right now.
Okay?
We're falling!
But we're so fast...
that we keep missing it.
That's a crazy way to think about it.
Jebediah!
Let's have a look, shall we?
Oy!
That's crazy.
I'm going to speed it up.
Oh!
Oh, so the rotation of the vessel stops when you increase time passage.
Otherwise, I guess the screen would go crazy.
Even faster.
Whoa!
Oh!
The Earth is getting smaller.
Or I mean, Kerbin.
I'm going to keep calling this the Earth for so long.
Oh, man.
Surely now, we're going to have some new crew reports.
No, we're still in space near Kerbin.
Okay.
Perpetuity is finally, well, almost perpetual.
We're not quite there yet.
We're at 2,000 meters per sec- Okay, we're actually going to go down to a lot less than I thought.
Okay!
Speed up more.
350 kilometer.
Look at that.
We almost have the entire planet in our field of view now.
So why don't we exact the opposite of, uh...
Perigee.
Like there.
Well, I guess it wouldn't be called Perigee since it's not Earth.
Hmm.
Speed up more.
I think...
That's...
No, a little more.
Now, we're going to burn a longer vector.
Wait, I can't fucking orient myself.
I'm looking at my spacecraft.
Oh, I guess I should...
Oh, yeah.
Oh, I guess this one is my vector, of course.
Just look at that one.
You ready?
We wouldn't need a lot here.
Oh, we're sort of...
On aligning now.
That should be enough.
Yeah, dude!
Orbit!
Achieved!
Wonderful!
Look at that.
Almost perfectly aligned with the...
Well...
Plane of the solar system here, but not quite.
We're a little off...
But that's because my steering is not perfect, you know?
That's okay.
If we had gone perfectly east, you know?
What a view.
Jebediah, are you excited?
Let me spin.
Reaction wheels working overtime.
What a view.
Jebediah, you shall not die this day.
In fact, you will die of hunger.
That's how you will die.
There's food over there, and there's not food.
I don't know how much food you brought, but...
This is so cool.
Let's try crew report now.
There we go!
Space high over Kerbin.
Crew reporting in from space.
Keep experiment.
Nice.
Let me actually try and click on some things here.
Toggle SAS.
Stability assist.
Toggle RCS.
Wait, how does that work?
Oh, okay, so it's like...
It's holding a fixed point?
Okay, that's nice.
Uh, I guess RCS would be if we had thrusters, but I don't have any of that.
Uh, it's short for...
Reaction control system.
That's how you would, like, fine-tune the orientation of a spacecraft.
I don't think you would use reaction wheels like that, the way we're doing here.
But then again, I'm not an expert on this.
Uh...
Docking mode.
Dude!
We're gonna make the interstellar docking sequence.
That's the first thing I think of now when I think of docking.
What the fuck?
Control mode.
I can't click on any of this.
Map.
Maneuver mode.
Oh, look at this!
We get to see orbital stuff.
Periapsis.
Apoapsis.
I thought it was called Perigee and Apogee.
Am I losing my mind?
But I guess that's just for Earth.
It's like you wouldn't say...
Translunar injection if you're going to...
Well, a body that's not the moon, right?
Time to reach.
Is there really that big a difference here?
Oh, I guess there is.
Haha!
Yeah, I guess.
I guess we could just go over here and slow down a bit.
But, uh, hold on.
We wanna come back.
And we still have fuel.
So, we wanna burn opposite, right?
We basically just wanna slow down so that we don't...
miss the curvature of the Earth anymore as we keep falling.
So that we actually start to hit the atmosphere.
And I guess we can start doing that now.
There's no reason to...
In fact, wait a minute...
Where's our, uh, original launch site?
It's here!
Let's see if we can get back exactly...
where we came from!
And not only that...
We're gonna land on the pad!
With the boot!
I'm kidding, we're not gonna have enough fuel for that.
Haha!
But we're gonna try and hit, uh, the space center.
I mean, we're already aligned.
We're on the equator here.
Hmm...
So I guess to do that, you would ideally...
I mean, we can do it now.
Let me see.
We're in opposite here.
Oh my god, it's so...
It's like...
Okay.
You know how in Elite Dangerous, if you play that game?
You have, um...
Flight Assist on, Flight Assist off?
This is essentially Flight Assist.
You know what I mean?
I like it.
Okay, so check it out.
Now we have to remember, as we hit the atmosphere, we're gonna start slowing down.
So...
Uh, our trajectory is actually gonna move that way as we go along.
Periapsis, 87 kilometers.
Let's make it...
Was it 65 we said?
Uh, more.
50.
This may not...
I mean, I don't know how much...
40 for sure there's a lot of air there, right?
I'm actually gonna...
No, more.
Let's say 30...
30.
Watch me hit the Space Center.
You ready?
In fact, I'm so sure...
I'm decoupling now.
Jebediah has the confidence...
Of a mammal.
A clever mammal.
Uh...
Speed up.
Faster.
Whoa.
Whoa!
Slow down, slow down, slow down.
God, this game is so...
Pretty, man.
Jebediah, you're coming home one way or the other.
Hehehehe.
Uh, I should probably start orienting...
Oh god, it's so...
It feels so weird with this on.
Like, it's like...
Look at that.
It's like instant.
The way it stops.
This feels weird.
I don't like that very much.
This feels more natural.
And then, when you reach it, you can go like that.
You know?
I'm gonna be printing the rest of those keys for next time.
But watch me slow down here.
Oh!
You hear that?
69!
I wonder if that's intentional.
Now we're gonna start hitting the atmosphere.
We're gonna slow down.
And Paragy's gonna go down.
And speed up a bit.
Here we go.
Oh god.
Dude, it's all coming back to me.
Oh!
Whoa, what's happening?
What?!
Perspective change.
We are moving very fast right now.
This is actually way faster than when we came in last time.
And there, it was already, like, super fast.
Oh!
Okay!
Look at the Jebediah!
He's a little nervous!
He's, like, a little...
You know this smile you make when you're, like, not quite sure?
That's his smile right now.
He's like, okay, keep calm.
Everything's...
Everything's fine.
Oh!
Look at that suborbital.
Ah!
We're not gonna hit it!
Oh, man!
I totally underestimated how much we're gonna slow down.
Shit!
Alright, well...
Jebediah, you're gonna be closer to home.
That's what matters.
You're not gonna be on the other side of the planet.
I think that matters.
Wait, if I turn this off...
T...
Look at the way it's automatically aligning.
This is actually better without this SAS.
Because it's...
It's following what it should be, you know, when it's falling in.
I don't have to control it.
This is...
This is like when you want it to be pointing in a very specific point on the bowl.
Right?
But this is naturally gonna follow this because...
I mean, that's the way the, uh...
You know...
The air's gonna...
Flow around the vessel and it's gonna align it automatically.
But I guess if this were to turn around, it would become more like a...
What do you call it?
Like a needle...
Shape.
And it would be more aerodynamic.
So it would be impossible to turn around after that.
So that's...
Kind of a problem, I guess.
Well, here we are!
Shoots!
Jebediah, you're coming home.
And would you look at that.
You didn't even eat all your snacks yet.
You still have some left.
Maybe you can share with the others.
Speed up.
And then at...
Two thousand...
Five hundred...
They're gonna deploy.
Actually, I could also just do the other one now.
Because we're slow enough.
Whoa!
There we go.
God, this is so freaking cool.
I love this game.
I mean, I loved it back then already, you know, but...
It's just such a genius concept for a game.
If you think about it.
And the weird thing is, like, even if it didn't have the campaign mode that we're on right now...
I think I still would have enjoyed it, you know?
Just not nearly as much, of course.
I really, really dig the slow progression of, like, getting more boosters and stuff like that.
It's also less overwhelming.
Hell yeah.
Where are we?
Looks like some kind of...
I don't know.
Oh, we're close to the water.
Are we in the desert?
Look at that!
Cacti!
I was about to say, um...
Tundra, but...
Alright.
Crew... Oh, wait, wait!
I don't want to do crew report, right?
Because we already did a good one.
But I guess I can...
EVA.
All hatches are obstructed, can't exit.
Oh.
Reaction wheel?
There you go.
Oh shit, no, no, oh no.
Oh shit, no, no.
Fuck!
Please be okay.
Okay, you know what, we're...
Can I just...
Stop rolling.
Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop.
Okay, I don't want to take any chances.
We recover that.
We're getting out of here.
And we got some science.
Very nice.
How many funds did we get?
How come I can't see how much money I actually earned?
This is just my total.
Ah well.
We got a lot.
Okay, I think that's a good point to stop.
We got to orbit.
I didn't reach the moon.
Next time for sure.
Now that we can build bigger rockets, man?
I mean, the moon is going to be a piece of cake.
Not a problem.
We got it.
Okay.
What do you think of that?
I want to know how many of you have not played this game.
Because I assume it's not going to be that many.
It's kind of a niche game, isn't it?
You haven't...
Oh, there's a lot of people.
So let me ask you.
What did you think of it?
What you saw?
Because I think it's straight up...
Incredibly addicting.
The gameplay loop of trying a rocket failing and then adding a little bit extra on it and trying again is so funny.
Nerdy but fun watching?
I mean, yeah.
I guess this is my sort of thing, right?
It's in your storage for more than five years and I still haven't.
I guess that's true for a lot of games for a lot of people.
It's like when Steam sale is on, you get like ten games.
And then you never touch them.
Yeah, trial and error is so much fun.
I don't know.
I kind of regret a little bit not picking the option where you can't revert.
Because if you think about it...
I'm never going to lose anyone.
Like, nobody's going to die.
Right?
Because I can just always revert and there's like no danger then.
That's why I was on the fence about it.
You can always choose not to revert.
You're right.
But you know, if the option is there, it feels kind of dumb not to do it.
So I kind of like it when games straight up forbid it.
You know what I mean?
I don't want to be tempted.
I don't think I have... I don't know.
You can change the difficulty.
Yeah, maybe I'll change it at some point.
Do you want to kill Jeb?
Yeah, I do actually.
Well, accidentally of course.
I don't want to do it on purpose.
But I do want this man to die at some point.
Think about it.
There's no drama without death.
You know?
Sometimes the physics glitch out so it's best to save.
I mean, I see that.
I see that argument.
That makes sense.
I understand that.
One Kerbal death so far, even though it was reverted.
Yeah, you're right actually.
We did kill one.
And maybe also others if I hadn't reverted.
I started reverting a little earlier in missions.
After getting used to it.
Be sure to disable crew response.
I don't know if I did that.
I just picked moderate as a difficulty.
I don't know if that's enabled or not in that mode.
You would have to tell me.
If it is.
It's already disabled for me.
Okay, perfect.
So I think what I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna keep going on moderate the way I have it right now.
And we're gonna get a bunch of knowledge.
And then in the future.
When I get a lot better at it.
And I have the knowledge.
Maybe we can transition over to a little more difficult.
You know?
Reverted flights are the simulations that a real space agency would do.
Oh my god man.
That's actually such a good argument.
I didn't think about that.
That's true.
But you know what?
We know what we should do then from now on.
This is actually such a good comment.
You're so right.
Here's what we're gonna do from now on.
We're gonna designate a simulation phase.
And then when we think we're ready.
We're gonna lock it off.
And say, this is the real deal.
And if we die now, it's over.
We will not revert.
You know what I mean?
And I say it before the mission starts.
So that I have nothing to argue with later.
You know?
Like...
I think that's a great middle ground.
Isn't that...
Fantastic?
Like we do the little...
Practice sessions in the simulator.
And then when it's time, for real, we suit up.
You know?
And...
Maybe we even...
Maybe I make a prediction for you guys as well.
You know?
Like...
Will the Kerbal survive or something?
I think that could be fun.
Exactly!
Twitch predictions for the real one.
Exactly.
You had the same idea as me.
We're on the same wavelength here.
But already learning these keybinds...
Helped so much.
Like the fact that you...
Have to go to the menu for that is crazy.
So I just started writing them down in the keybind section.
You know?
I have like six of them written down now.
Cooking stream now.
It's about dinner time.
But the thing is...
I will do a cooking stream.
I just need the equipment for it.
I'm thinking of getting a camera...
That I can strap on my head.
Similar to Kenji.
If you know him on YouTube...
I watch his videos a lot.
And he has this sort of POV...
Where he's cooking with the thing on his head.
Because setting up one camera with one camera angle...
Is gonna be so cumbersome for me.
And maybe you can...
I don't know...
Stream it...
Wirelessly to...
My computer.
And then it can go on OBS or something.
There's gotta be a way to do that.
How far do you simulate?
Before committing?
Or do you do a successful simulation?
I guess...
It would be...
Based on feel.
You know?
If I feel like...
Okay.
The next one is it.
Then I'll just say it.
You know?
It depends on when I say it.
But I mean...
If I do a successful one...
Um...
Well I guess that's a good point.
If I just happen to make it...
Well then I just make it right?
Then there's no...
Then I just...
Go back and say...
Well that was the real one.
No reason to redo it I guess.
I guess that's what I would do there.
When is the next Minecraft stream?
I would say tomorrow.
Let's say tomorrow on that.
Tomorrow's Minecraft.
Cause I'm...
I'm actually itching to get back into that.
I discovered a bunch of new shit.
In the last Minecraft stream.
Which was a while ago.
I took a break, remember?
So I wanna...
I wanna get into that.
And it's probably gonna be the same time.
So around 14, 15-ish.
CEST.
Now let's launch some Kerbals.
You came at the wrong time, man.
We're ending it now.
We just did.
We launched a bunch.
In fact, it was mostly Jebediah.
And also, uh...
Valentine.
Looking away from the screen makes my vision wobbly.
Because of the photo.
What do you mean, man?
There's no wobbling here.
I think you're on to...
You're smoking something.
What are you making?
The hotel factory?
Um...
Are you talking about...
The hotel for Minecraft factory?
Hmm...
I don't know.
When I find a hotel, I guess.
That would be the first step, right?
Otherwise, I can't really...
Do anything.
We can see that you really enjoyed it.
Man, I knew I was gonna enjoy it.
Because I've already played it, right?
I know this game is amazing.
I just didn't get very far.
And I played it in a very early access state.
When pretty much everything was...
I mean...
Pretty bad.
You know?
The game is completely different, though.
The game even looks completely different.
And even without the mods, it still looked different.
Like, back then, it was...
It was really bad.
Right?
The visual mods are amazing.
One of them I had to pay for.
Which is...
Kinda weird.
For a... mod.
But...
I did my research on it, and everyone was saying, You gotta get that mod, you know?
So, I was like...
Fine.
What mods have I installed?
I have installed...
I can tell you.
Uh...
One sec.
Let me give you the list.
I'm using CCAN...
To install mods.
Oh my god.
It's not even sorting by...
Installed.
I guess a bunch of these are dependencies.
But there's...
B9 part switch.
Click through blocker.
I don't even remember installing this.
This must be dependency.
Um...
Deferred.
Distant object enhancement.
Firefly.
Harmony 2.
Copernicus planetary system modifier.
KSP community fixes.
Texture loader.
Burst compiler.
Burst plugin.
These are all dependencies.
Has to be.
Modular flight integrator.
Module manager.
Parallax.
Continued.
Shabby.
Stock waterfall effects.
Toolbar controller.
Tough X.
And waterfall core.
And scatterer.
And then the...
The...
Cloud mod.
Which I don't think was on CCAN.
Did you pick all the mods?
I basically just googled the...
Essential graphical mods.
For a...
Kerbal Space program.
And then I did some testing.
You know.
To make it look good in game.
Before I started.
And...
I noticed a couple bugs.
Like with the audio.
So I fixed that.
On my own.
But other than that.
I didn't really do anything.
And some other...
Smaller minor things.
Will you try balance?
It's short.
What is balance?
Let me see.
Oh yeah.
You weren't kidding.
Seems like a small game.
Two...
Two euros.
What a random game to suggest.
Is that game really like...
That good?
I just wanna...
You just wanna see me play balance man.
You gotta balance that ball.
Seems like a...
Is it a game where you have to use like a...
Gamepad and then...
Motion controls or something?
What if...
What are the rules if a bug causes mission failure?
Oh, in that case we're just gonna revert.
I think.
Unless it's like...
A mission that I would've failed anyway.
You know, we use our...
Brains for that.
We just use logic and go...
Oh, you know...
Was it super unfair in that case?
Go back.
If it wasn't super unfair...
And it wouldn't have changed anything anyway...
Then...
Whatever.
We're just gonna die, right?
It's actually...
Ball and...
Oh!
That makes so much sense actually.
Bug in the simulation software.
Oh yeah!
That's another way to say it, I guess.
Ah!
Look!
Oh God!
You thought it was real?
It was all a simulation!
Are you up for VR game suggestions?
Or not really into that?
I actually don't have a VR headset right now.
I sold my last one.
When I started doing...
Streaming full time.
Because I needed...
Some money.
But...
I'm actually considering buying the...
The...
The new Valve one.
I did see it was kind of expensive though, but...
If there's a lot of good games for it, maybe I'll consider it actually.
And you know, it's a tax write-off.
Because it's...
You know...
For the company!
So it would work that way.
It would make it a little bit cheaper.
It's worth it.
What other games are there that are so good nowadays in VR?
I haven't really been following that.
I played Half-Life Alyx already, and that game was phenomenal.
I can't...
I can't even see anything topping that.
But who knows?
I haven't...
Been keeping track.
Yeah, I already played Half-Life Alyx, but it's a great suggestion, Jan.
Five Nights at Freddy's exists in VR?
Oh my God, get the fuck out of here.
I would die from that, okay?
I would literally have my heart stopped, I think.
It's not good.
There's a bunch of small ones.
Yeah, I feel like if there was a really big one, I would have heard about it.
You know?
But, hello!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Minecraft!
Can be played in VR, right?
And it's quite good in VR, apparently, too.
Like, it's...
It's not like a janky solution, either.
It's like fully...
Fully VR.
I said this in the past, but I think that could be really fun to try.
But first, of course, I gotta get a VR headset.
Subnautica has a VR mode.
I actually read about that in the past, and I heard it's terrible.
It's apparently not performant.
It's, like, lagging.
You don't have hand controls.
It's, you know, you aim with your head and stuff.
I don't like that.
If I'm playing VR, it needs to be fully supported, you know?
Motion controls, good performance, stuff like that.
But, who knows if Subnautica has become better in that regard.
It officially supports VR?
Okay, that's new.
I'm pretty sure it was a mod that I heard about in the past.
Maybe I should give it a shot, then.
The Moist Criticals team spent 24 hours in Minecraft VR.
Damn, dude.
Just spending 24 hours in Pancake VR seems kinda hard for someone like me who's getting older, you know?
24 hours!
I mean, unless you count sleeping.
In that case, I could do it, but...
Yeah.
Staying up for 24 hours nowadays?
I'm too old for that.
Yeah, I was thinking about Vivecraft.
That's the one I was thinking of.
That's apparently the really good one.
I feel you unk me too.
What does that mean, pest?
Is that some...
some new young people slogan?
How old are you?
I'm 34.
And I just got referred, actually.
I mentioned this ADHD thing.
I just got referred today by my doctor to contact a psychiatrist to have them figure out if...
there's something there.
So we'll see.
The doctor actually got back to me, like she said she would.
She gave me, like, a questionnaire.
Exactly the same one I had gotten in the past.
And I answered it as truthfully as I could.
And then she was like, okay, I mean, you...
you check the amount needed for me to send you on to the next.
Doesn't mean you necessarily have anything, but...
I'm gonna let the psychiatry person...
judge that, you know?
So I'm being sent along for that.
So we'll see what happens.
I mean, you know.
We'll see.
It's exciting, I guess.
Apparently there's a long wait time.
These psychiatrists are very booked.
I can also recommend Superhot VR.
Brother!
I love Superhot VR!
It's probably one of the best VR games out there.
I've played it already, man.
It is such a good game.
In fact, it's one of my favorite games ever.
It is...
beautiful in VR.
It is like better in VR than Pancake.
Way better.
It was made for VR without...
before VR even became a thing.
Beat Saber was also good.
But wasn't nearly as good as Superhot for me.
Doom VFR?
Maybe.
I haven't tried it.
Sounds like a little scary thing.
Heavily modded Skyrim VR is pretty peak.
I've always wanted to play Skyrim anyways.
Maybe VR...
for a first playthrough could be fun, you know?
It's an old game at this point, though.
What even is a pancake?
It's just an expression for...
When you've tried VR games, you start calling old 2D games, you know, on a monitor for pancake games.
You've never played Skyrim?
I haven't, but I know a lot about it.
I mean, I maybe tried it once at some point.
But I never really played it at all.
Like, I know all the memes.
I know Fus Roda and...
you know, arrow to the knee and stuff like that.
But I haven't actually, you know, played it.
For real.
I actually had it on my poll a couple times.
What about Death Stranding?
Played it.
Loved it.
Solid suggestion, Joshua.
Love that game.
Looking forward to playing the second one.
Yeah, I thought it was peak for sure.
A lot of people didn't like it because the gameplay is a little, you know, different.
But I really enjoyed it.
I liked taking it slow and taking in the environments.
It was right up my alley.
A Fisherman's Tale is also an interesting VR game.
It's Puzzle Adventure.
Oh, that sounds nice.
If I get to fish as well and do puzzles, that sounds like a winner.
But I guess if I ever get a VR headset, I would probably immediately start researching everything there is to play that's worth playing nowadays.
So a lot of these suggestions I probably would find on my own as well.
No, it's not going to be a horror game this October unless I find something that, you know, is more like unsettling atmosphere but no, like, jump scares, you know what I mean?
Maybe I'll find something like that.
Or I will do another episode of Five Nights at Freddy's but I will literally, and I mean this 100% from my heart, put duct tape over my mouth.
Because I think that could be fun just for the stupidity of it.
Like, I'm not even kidding, I'm 100% serious.
I think that could be funny.
If only for an hour, you know, just to see...
Put a gag as well...
What?
No!
Fuck that, no way.
That's horrible.
I think it's enough with a...
With some duct tape.
Ah, but wait a minute, I have beard.
Ah, should I shake?
That's horrible with duct tape though.
Hmm...
I'll have to think about that.
There's gotta be a better way.
Use glue instead.
No, man, no!
That's horrible.
Oh, imagine gluing your mouth together.
Oh, shit.
Oh my god, that's actually nightmare fuel.
No balls?
Definitely not.
My balls have been shrunk to...
Well, you can't see them anymore, they're gone.
There's a BDSM tape that sticks to itself.
Hey!
Maybe that's it.
Maybe that's what I need to go for.
And then a webcam as well, and then people are really gonna be confused when they enter my stream.
Seeing me play...
Five Nights at Freddy's with a ball gag in my mouth.
And someone behind me with like a...
Like a whip.
Oh no, that's horrible.
Oh, that's horrible.
Why am I even thinking about this?
I guess because you guys put the idea in my mind.
Okay, you know what?
Also, I realize that the chat on screen right now is a little gimmicky.
You know?
I thought it would be cool to animate it like that, but...
Honestly, you can't really read it that well.
I may have to change it for next time.
I was thinking like it was gonna be like an orbit, you know?
Like planets and shit.
But yeah.
Maybe I'll figure out a better solution.
Guys, I'm out of here.
It's time for me to eat.
And I'm also gonna eat Jackie.
For dinner.
No, I mean Jackie's gonna eat dinner.
And yeah.
Thank you for watching.
I'll see you in the next stream tomorrow.
It's gonna be Minecraft.
It's gonna be great.
Trains.
And other things.
Have a nice evening and a wonderful week.
Bye-bye.